[
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-1-q2", "unit": 6, "question": "The wings of bats, birds, and butterflies are an example of structures", "options": ["homologous", "vestigial", "endemic", "homeostatic", "analogous"], "answer": 4, "keywords": ["wings", "bats", "birds", "butterflies", "homologous", "vestigial", "endemic", "homeostatic", "analogous"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-1-q5", "unit": 8, "question": "Which of the following is a density-independent factor limiting human population growth?", "options": ["Fatal car accidents", "Tornados", "Epidemics", "Famine", "Pollution"], "answer": 1, "keywords": ["density-independent", "human population", "growth", "fatal", "car accidents", "tornados", "epidemics", "famine", "pollution"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-1-q6", "unit": 9, "question": "What is the function of the valves in the vessels of the human circulatory system?", "options": ["To prevent the backflow of blood", "To prevent blood from advancing too rapidly", "Stop the forward movement of blood clots", "Support the structure of the blood vessel", "Provide a site for the attachment of capillaries"], "answer": 0, "keywords": ["valves", "vessels", "human circulatory system", "backflow", "blood", "blood clots", "capillaries"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-1-q7", "unit": 2, "question": "The product of meiosis of a diploid cell is", "options": ["2 genetically identical diploid cells.", "4 genetically different diploid cells.", "2 genetically identical haploid cells.", "4 genetically different haploid cells.", "4 genetically identical haploid cells."], "answer": 3, "keywords": ["meiosis", "diploid", "genetically", "identical", "different", "haploid"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-1-q8", "unit": 9, "question": "Which of the following body systems is least involved in the body's response to a pathogen?", "options": ["Integumentary", "Immune", "Cardiovascular", "Lymphatic", "Excretory"], "answer": 4, "keywords": ["body systems", "pathogen", "integumentary", "immune", "cardiovascular", "lymphatic", "excretory"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-1-q9", "unit": 10, "question": "Many patients want doctors to prescribe antibiotics at the first sign of illness. Why are doctors hesitant to do this for the long-term safety of the human population?", "options": ["People may develop immunity to the antibiotic.", "Overuse of antibiotics contributes to the development of antibiotic-resistant pathogens.", "The supply of antibiotics is limited.", "Overuse of antibiotics can lead to genetic mutations in humans.", "Antibiotics inhibit the growth of viruses but not of bacteria."], "answer": 1, "keywords": ["antibiotics", "immunity", "overuse", "antibiotic-resistant", "pathogens", "genetic mutations", "viruses", "bacteria"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-1-q10", "unit": 3, "question": "Which of the following is NOT a product of aerobic respiration?", "options": ["ATP", "O2", "H2O", "CO2", "All are products."], "answer": 1, "keywords": ["aerobic respiration", "atp", "o2", "h2o", "co2"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-1-q11", "unit": 7, "question": "The first time a child touches something hot, he will withdraw his hand quickly. This reflex is an example of", "options": ["trial and error learning.", "an innate behavior.", "classical conditioning.", "imprinting.", "operant conditioning."], "answer": 1, "keywords": ["reflex", "trial and error learning", "innate behavior", "classical conditioning", "imprinting", "operant conditioning"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-1-q13", "unit": 2, "question": "What is the role of DNA ligase during DNA replication?", "options": ["It synthesizes DNA nucleotides.", "It provides a template for the lengthening of telomeres.", "It joins sections of DNA to form the new DNA strand.", "It unwinds the DNA double helix at the start of replication.", "It removes non-complementary DNA nucleotides in the newly formed DNA strand."], "answer": 2, "keywords": ["dna ligase", "dna replication", "nucleotides", "template", "telomeres", "dna double helix"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-1-q14", "unit": 5, "question": "In humans, right-handedness is dominant to left-handedness. Two right-handed individuals have a child who is left-handed. What is the probability that their next child will be left-handed?", "options": ["0%", "25%", "50%", "75%", "100%"], "answer": 1, "keywords": ["right-handedness", "dominant", "left-handedness", "probability"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-1-q15", "unit": 1, "question": "A human liver cell is placed in pure water. The cell will", "options": ["swell, because water will enter the cell.", "swell, because solutes will enter the cell.", "stay approximately the same volume, because water and solutes will move in both directions across the membrane at approximately the same rate.", "shrink, because water will leave the cell.", "shrink, because solutes will leave the cell."], "answer": 0, "keywords": ["human liver cell", "pure water", "swell", "solutes", "membrane", "shrink"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-1-q17", "unit": 1, "question": "DNA is a polymer made of repeating smaller units, or monomers, called", "options": ["monosaccharides.", "amino acids.", "mRNA.", "nucleotides.", "nucleic acids."], "answer": 3, "keywords": ["dna", "polymer", "monomers", "monosaccharides", "amino acids", "mrna", "nucleotides", "nucleic acids"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-1-q18", "unit": 4, "question": "In gene regulation, which of the following removes the repressor to allow the transcription of the gene?", "options": ["Ubiquitin", "Inducer", "Promoter", "Repressor", "Corepressor"], "answer": 1, "keywords": ["gene regulation", "repressor", "transcription", "ubiquitin", "inducer", "promoter", "corepressor"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-1-q20", "unit": 3, "question": "During what phase of photosynthesis is carbon dioxide fixed?", "options": ["Light dependent", "Light independent", "Oxidation of water", "Electron transport", "Photon absorption"], "answer": 1, "keywords": ["photosynthesis", "carbon dioxide", "light dependent", "light independent", "oxidation", "electron transport", "photon absorption"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-2-q1", "unit": 10, "question": "Which of the following vectors is responsible for the transmission of malaria?", "options": ["Mosquito", "Louse", "Tick", "Flea", "Fly"], "answer": 0, "keywords": ["vectors", "transmission", "malaria", "mosquito"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-2-q2", "unit": 9, "question": "Animals can communicate with another animal of the same species through chemicals called", "options": ["inducers.", "imprinters.", "adrenalines.", "neurotransmitters.", "pheromones."], "answer": 4, "keywords": ["animal communication", "species", "chemicals", "pheromones"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-2-q3", "unit": 8, "question": "Which of the following levels of biological organization is arranged in the correct sequence from simplest to most complex?", "options": ["Community, Population, Ecosystem", "Community, Ecosystem, Population", "Ecosystem, Community, Population", "Population, Ecosystem, Community", "Population, Community, Ecosystem"], "answer": 4, "keywords": ["biological organization", "population", "community", "ecosystem"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-2-q4", "unit": 8, "question": "The Australian Christmas Tree is a flowering tree that severs the root xylem of neighboring plants, inserting its haustoria into its neighbor's water supply. The Christmas tree plant drains the water of these neighboring plants for its own use without providing any benefit to the other plant. Which of the following best describes the interactions between these plants?", "options": ["Mutualism", "Parasitism", "Commensalism", "Facilitation", "Competition"], "answer": 1, "keywords": ["australian christmas tree", "flowering tree", "xylem", "haustoria", "parasitism"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-2-q5", "unit": 8, "question": "A moth that has two large eyespots on its wings looks like a much larger animal. It will probably be able to avoid", "options": ["commensalism.", "parasitism.", "symbiosis.", "predation.", "competition."], "answer": 3, "keywords": ["moth", "eyespots", "mimicry", "predation"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-2-q6", "unit": 1, "question": "When water vaporizes, what type of bonds are broken?", "options": ["ionic bonds", "polar covalent bonds", "hydrogen bonds", "both hydrogen bonds and ionic bonds", "both polar covalent bonds and hydrogen bonds"], "answer": 2, "keywords": ["water", "vaporization", "hydrogen bonds"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-2-q7", "unit": 1, "question": "Structures found in the cells of both angiosperms and mammals are", "options": ["cell walls and cell membranes.", "centrioles and lysosomes.", "chloroplasts and ribosomes.", "ribosomes and Golgi bodies.", "none of these are found in both."], "answer": 3, "keywords": ["angiosperms", "mammals", "ribosomes", "golgi bodies"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-2-q11", "unit": 2, "question": "Which of the following statements best describes proto-oncogenes?", "options": ["They suppress tumor growth in somatic cells.", "They are genes that are introduced to a cell by viruses.", "They are produced by somatic mutations caused by carcinogenic mutagens.", "They code for proteins that control cell growth.", "They cause genetic cancers in somatic cells."], "answer": 3, "keywords": ["proto-oncogenes", "tumor growth", "somatic cells", "cell growth"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-2-q12", "unit": 5, "question": "In guinea pigs, black hair (B) is dominant to brown hair and short hair (H) is dominant to long hair. A female guinea pig that is BbHH has children with a male that is BBHh. Which of the following is not a possible genotype in the children?", "options": ["BBHH", "Bbhh", "BbHh", "BbHH", "BBHh"], "answer": 1, "keywords": ["guinea pigs", "genotype", "dominant", "mendelian inheritance", "punnett square"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-2-q13", "unit": 2, "question": "A diploid cell has three pairs of homologous chromosomes identified as A1/A2, B1/B2, and C1/C2. What chromosome combination below is most likely to be found in a cell that is the result of meiosis?", "options": ["Al and C1", "Al and A2", "A2, B1, and C2", "A1, A1, B1, B1, C1, and C1", "A1, A2, B1, B2, C1, and C2"], "answer": 2, "keywords": ["diploid", "homologous chromosomes", "meiosis", "haploid"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-2-q14", "unit": 2, "question": "Which of the following is characteristic of the lytic cycle?", "options": ["Many bacterial cells containing viral DNA are produced.", "Viral DNA is incorporated into the host genome and is replicated with the host for generations.", "The viral genome replicates independently of the host cell and viruses are released by exocytosis without destroying the host cell.", "A large number of viral phages are released at one time when the host cell bursts.", "The virus destroys the host DNA and forces the host cell to morph into a virus."], "answer": 3, "keywords": ["lytic cycle", "viral dna", "host genome", "phages", "exocytosis"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-2-q16", "unit": 3, "question": "Noncompetitive inhibitors decrease the rate of an enzyme reaction by", "options": ["binding at the active site of the enzyme.", "changing the shape of the enzyme's active site.", "decreasing the free energy of the reactant.", "removing the coenzyme for the reaction.", "increasing the activation energy of the reaction."], "answer": 1, "keywords": ["noncompetitive inhibitors", "enzyme reaction", "active site", "allosteric regulation"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-2-q17", "unit": 6, "question": "In a population of finches, one group of birds has a short, parrotlike beak and another group has a long, narrow beak. What process has probably occurred?", "options": ["Genetic drift", "Gene flow", "Directional selection", "Disruptive selection", "Stabilizing selection"], "answer": 3, "keywords": ["finches", "beak", "natural selection", "disruptive selection"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-2-q18", "unit": 9, "question": "A neuron at rest has a negative resting potential due to a higher concentration of _______ cations outside of the cell.", "options": ["positive, hydrogen", "positive, potassium", "positive, sodium", "negative, potassium", "negative, sodium"], "answer": 4, "keywords": ["neuron", "resting potential", "cations", "sodium-potassium pump"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-2-q19", "unit": 7, "question": "Speciation occurred in a population of frogs when one group began breeding in early spring and the other in early summer. This separation of a population that causes the formation of new species is called", "options": ["post-zygotic", "behavioral", "geographic", "homeotic", "temporal"], "answer": 4, "keywords": ["speciation", "frogs", "temporal isolation", "reproductive isolation"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-2-q20", "unit": 9, "question": "Which body system is responsible for delivering carbon dioxide to the lungs and waste products to the kidneys?", "options": ["circulatory", "respiratory", "excretory", "digestive", "lymphatic"], "answer": 0, "keywords": ["body system", "carbon dioxide", "lungs", "waste products", "kidneys", "circulatory system"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-3-q1", "unit": 10, "question": "Which of the following is not a typical symptom of malaria?", "options": ["fever and chills", "rash", "headache", "fatigue and body aches", "jaundice"], "answer": 1, "keywords": ["symptom", "malaria", "fever", "chills", "rash", "headache", "fatigue", "body aches", "jaundice"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-3-q2", "unit": 8, "question": "Two dogs meet for the first time. They sniff each other, then one dog rolls over to expose its belly. This is an example of behavior.", "options": ["imprinting", "agonistic", "territorial", "learned", "conditioning"], "answer": 1, "keywords": ["dogs", "sniff", "expose belly", "behavior", "imprinting", "agonistic", "territorial", "learned", "conditioning"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-3-q3", "unit": 8, "question": "Which of the following is not a method used by plants to protect themselves from herbivores?", "options": ["nicotine", "cryptic coloration", "spines", "thorns", "thick, hard leaves"], "answer": 1, "keywords": ["plants", "protection", "herbivores", "nicotine", "cryptic coloration", "spines", "thorns", "leaves"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-3-q4", "unit": 8, "question": "In the late 1880's, a large deciduous forest was clear cut by logging companies for the harvesting of wood products. The land was colonized by grasses which were eventually replaced by shrubs then trees. The grasses held the soil in place during the rainy season which allowed for the colonization by the shrubs and trees. Which of the following best describes the processes involved in this progression from grasses to trees?", "options": ["Primary succession; Facilitation", "Primary succession; Inhibition", "Primary succession; Toleration", "Secondary succession; Facilitation", "Secondary succession; Inhibition"], "answer": 3, "keywords": ["forest", "logging", "grasses", "shrubs", "trees", "soil", "colonization", "secondary succession", "facilitation"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-3-q5", "unit": 1, "question": "When two atoms are equally electronegative, they will interact to form", "options": ["hydrogen bonds.", "van der Waals interactions.", "polar covalent bonds.", "nonpolar covalent bonds.", "ionic bonds."], "answer": 3, "keywords": ["atoms", "electronegative", "hydrogen bonds", "van der waals", "polar covalent bonds", "nonpolar covalent bonds", "ionic bonds"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-3-q9", "unit": 2, "question": "Movement of the chromosomes during anaphase would be most affected by a drug that", "options": ["reduces G1/S cyclin concentrations.", "prevents the formation of the cell plate.", "prevents elongation of microtubules.", "prevents shortening of microtubules.", "prevents attachment of the microtubules to the kinetochore."], "answer": 3, "keywords": ["chromosomes", "anaphase", "drug", "cyclin", "cell plate", "microtubules", "elongation", "shortening", "kinetochore"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-3-q10", "unit": 10, "question": "In colorectal cancer, several genes must be mutated for a non-cancerous cell to become cancerous. A mutation in genes that is most likely to cause colorectal cancer.", "options": ["code for the mucus lining of the digestive tract", "code for digestive enzymes", "control the cell cycle", "code for hormones that control the rate of digestion", "cause all cancers"], "answer": 2, "keywords": ["colorectal cancer", "genes", "mutated", "non-cancerous", "cancerous", "mutation", "mucus lining", "digestive enzymes", "cell cycle", "hormones"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-3-q11", "unit": 4, "question": "Which of the following is an example of post-transcriptional control of gene expression?", "options": ["Repetitive copying of DNA segments in gene amplification.", "The addition of methyl groups to cytosine in DNA.", "The binding of transcription factors to a promoter.", "The removal of introns from the mRNA transcript.", "The folding of DNA to form heterochromatin."], "answer": 3, "keywords": ["post-transcriptional", "control", "gene expression", "dna segments", "gene amplification", "methyl groups", "cytosine", "transcription factors", "promoter", "introns", "mrna", "heterochromatin"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-3-q12", "unit": 5, "question": "Which of the following statements best describes the difference between reproductive cloning and therapeutic cloning?", "options": ["Reproductive cloning produces copies of genes that are inserted into embryonic cells by viral vectors.", "Therapeutic cloning uses totipotent cells to produce an entire organism.", "The purpose of reproductive cloning is the treatment of infertility in humans.", "Therapeutic cloning transplants a nuclear-transfer blastocyst into a surrogate mother.", "Reproductive cloning produces copies of whole animals; therapeutic cloning creates tissues to replace damaged body parts."], "answer": 4, "keywords": ["reproductive cloning", "therapeutic cloning", "genes", "embryonic cells", "viral vectors", "totipotent", "organism", "infertility", "nuclear-transfer", "blastocyst", "surrogate mother", "tissues"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-3-q13", "unit": 5, "question": "A man with normal blood clotting marries a woman who is heterozygous for hemophilia (X^h). If they were to have children, what would be the likelihood that their son would have hemophilia?", "options": ["0%", "25%", "50%", "75%", "100%"], "answer": 2, "keywords": ["blood clotting", "heterozygous", "hemophilia", "children", "son", "punnett square", "x-linked"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-3-q14", "unit": 3, "question": "Which of the following could increase the rate of photosynthesis in plants?", "options": ["Increased concentrations of oxygen in the spaces around the stomata.", "Increased photorespiration.", "Decreased concentration of rubisco in the photosynthetic tissues.", "Increased carbon dioxide concentrations in the air spaces of the leaf.", "Decreased frequency of stomata openings."], "answer": 3, "keywords": ["rate", "photosynthesis", "plants", "oxygen", "stomata", "photorespiration", "rubisco", "carbon dioxide", "leaf"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-3-q15", "unit": 6, "question": "In a population in Hardy-Weinberg equilibrium, the frequency of the recessive allele is 0.26. What is the frequency of heterozygous individuals?", "options": ["0.74", "0.55", "0.38", "0.26", "0.07"], "answer": 2, "keywords": ["hardy-weinberg", "equilibrium", "recessive allele", "frequency", "heterozygous"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-3-q16", "unit": 9, "question": "Cell-mediated immunity is a type of acquired immunity that is effective in removing virus infected cells. Which of the following types of immune cells are mainly involved in cell-mediated immunity?", "options": ["T cells", "B cells", "Erythrocytes", "Neutrophils", "Eosinophils"], "answer": 0, "keywords": ["cell-mediated immunity", "acquired immunity", "virus", "immune cells", "t cells", "b cells", "erythrocytes", "neutrophils", "eosinophils"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-3-q17", "unit": 10, "question": "Which of the following is NOT a method of transmission of a communicable disease?", "options": ["Eating contaminated food", "Inheritance from parent", "Insect bites", "Sexual intercourse", "Touching contaminated surfaces"], "answer": 1, "keywords": ["transmission", "communicable disease", "food", "inheritance", "insect bites", "sexual intercourse", "contaminated surfaces"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-3-q18", "unit": 6, "question": "A species of mollusks has not changed significantly for thousands of years. A sudden change in their environment causes a rapid evolutionary change in their inherited characteristics. This is an example of", "options": ["punctuated equilibrium.", "convergent evolution.", "parallel evolution.", "homology.", "gradualism."], "answer": 0, "keywords": ["species", "mollusks", "environment", "evolutionary change", "inherited characteristics", "punctuated equilibrium", "convergent evolution", "parallel evolution", "homology", "gradualism"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-3-q20", "unit": 9, "question": "How do the circulatory system and immune system work together to respond to injury?", "options": ["Decreased blood flow to the injury kills the surrounding cells which stops bleeding at the site.", "Increased blood flow removes infected cells from the site of injury and carries them to the excretory system for removal.", "Increased blood flow increases the number of leukocytes at the injury to prevent infection.", "Increased blood flow allows for an increase in the exchange of O2 and CO2 at the site of the injury.", "Decreased blood flow to the injury limits nutrients to bacteria which prevents the spread of infection."], "answer": 2, "keywords": ["circulatory system", "immune system", "injury", "blood flow", "leukocytes", "infection", "o2", "co2", "nutrients", "bacteria"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-4-q2", "unit": 1, "question": "Small membrane sacs inside eukaryotic cells can detoxify poisons and oxidize fatty acids and amino acids. Hydrogen peroxide, which is a dangerous byproduct of these reactions, is safely contained within this organelle called the", "options": ["centrosome", "vacuole", "Golgi apparatus", "peroxisome", "endoplasmic reticulum"], "answer": 3, "keywords": ["eukaryotic", "detoxify", "fatty acids", "amino acids", "hydrogen peroxide", "organelle", "peroxisome"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-4-q3", "unit": 3, "question": "What happens to the oxygen that is produced by plants during photosynthesis?", "options": ["It is oxidized to form carbon dioxide.", "It is reduced to form carbon dioxide.", "It is oxidized to form water.", "It is reduced to form water.", "It is released as waste."], "answer": 4, "keywords": ["oxygen", "plants", "photosynthesis", "carbon dioxide", "water", "waste"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-4-q4", "unit": 6, "question": "A pattern of evolution in which two different species with similar evolutionary pressures become more similar over time is called", "options": ["convergent evolution.", "coevolution.", "adaptive radiation.", "fitness.", "punctuated equilibrium."], "answer": 0, "keywords": ["evolution", "species", "evolutionary pressures", "convergent evolution", "coevolution", "adaptive radiation", "fitness", "punctuated equilibrium"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-4-q7", "unit": 2, "question": "In DNA replication, DNA polymerase III catalyzes the reaction in which", "options": ["the double helix unwinds.", "the sugar-phosphate bonds of each strand are broken.", "a phosphate group is added to the 3'- carbon of ribose.", "a nucleotide with a complimentary base is added to the developing DNA strand.", "a RNA primer is synthesized."], "answer": 3, "keywords": ["dna replication", "dna polymerase iii", "double helix", "sugar-phosphate bonds", "phosphate", "ribose", "nucleotide", "complimentary base", "rna primer"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-4-q8", "unit": 3, "question": "Which of the following is NOT true of the electron transport chain?", "options": ["ATP molecules are produced.", "NADH drops off electrons to carrier molecules in the electron transport chain.", "Oxygen is the final electron acceptor.", "H+ pumped across the mitochondrial membrane.", "Carbon dioxide is released as a waste product."], "answer": 4, "keywords": ["electron transport chain", "atp", "nadh", "electrons", "carrier molecules", "oxygen", "final electron acceptor", "mitochondrial membrane", "carbon dioxide"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-4-q10", "unit": 7, "question": "Gram positive bacteria appear purple under a light microscope when treated with a differential stain that includes crystal violet. A thick layer of ________ in the cell wall retains the violet stain despite a decolorization treatment.", "options": ["chitin", "cellulose", "lipopolysaccharide", "cholesterol", "peptidoglycan"], "answer": 4, "keywords": ["gram positive", "bacteria", "microscope", "differential stain", "crystal violet", "cell wall", "chitin", "cellulose", "lipopolysaccharide", "cholesterol", "peptidoglycan"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-4-q11", "unit": 10, "question": "In 2022, 94% of all malaria cases were from", "options": ["South America", "Central America", "North America", "Africa", "Asia"], "answer": 3, "keywords": ["malaria", "africa", "epidemiology"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-4-q12", "unit": 4, "question": "_________ is the process that makes a copy of a gene from DNA, and _________ is the process that synthesizes the protein.", "options": ["Replication, transcription", "Replication, translation", "Translation, transcription", "Transcription, translation", "Translation, replication"], "answer": 3, "keywords": ["gene", "dna", "protein", "replication", "transcription", "translation"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-4-q13", "unit": 9, "question": "Which part of the vertebrate nephron consists of a cluster of capillaries where waste products are filtered from the blood?", "options": ["Bowman's capsule", "glomerulus", "loop of Henle", "distal tubule", "collecting tubule"], "answer": 1, "keywords": ["vertebrate", "nephron", "capillaries", "blood", "bowman's capsule", "glomerulus", "loop of henle", "distal tubule", "collecting tubule"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-4-q14", "unit": 5, "question": "If 20% of a DNA sample is made up of thymine, T, what percentage of the sample is made up of cytosine, C?", "options": ["15%", "30%", "35%", "50%", "80%"], "answer": 1, "keywords": ["dna", "thymine", "cytosine", "chargaff's rule"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-4-q15", "unit": 9, "question": "The function of antibodies is to", "options": ["engulf pathogens by endocytosis.", "destroy pathogens by injecting toxins.", "attract macrophages to an injury by releasing cytokines.", "release perforins attach to and perforate infected cells.", "mark pathogenic cells for destruction."], "answer": 4, "keywords": ["antibodies", "pathogens", "endocytosis", "toxins", "macrophages", "cytokines", "perforins", "infected cells"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-4-q16", "unit": 4, "question": "How does methylation affect the activity of a DNA segment?", "options": ["It causes DNA to replicate continuously.", "It causes DNA to unzip and unwind in preparation for protein synthesis.", "It slows the process of transcription and translation.", "It causes the DNA segment to become mobile and \"jump\" to a new location in the genome.", "It induces protein synthesis by blocking binding sites for repressors."], "answer": 2, "keywords": ["methylation", "dna", "replicate", "protein synthesis", "transcription", "translation", "genome", "repressors"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-4-q17", "unit": 6, "question": "Advances in transportation have allowed humans to move across the globe and settle in another country. This has decreased the differences between populations by increasing", "options": ["the founder effect.", "nonrandom mating.", "geographic isolation.", "genetic drift.", "gene flow."], "answer": 4, "keywords": ["populations", "founder effect", "nonrandom mating", "geographic isolation", "genetic drift", "gene flow"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-4-q18", "unit": 4, "question": "A frameshift mutation can result from", "options": ["addition of 1-2 nucleotides.", "deletion of 3 nucleotides.", "substitution of a nucleotide.", "two nucleotides switching places.", "an extra chromosome."], "answer": 0, "keywords": ["frameshift mutation", "nucleotides", "deletion", "substitution", "chromosome"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-4-q19", "unit": 5, "question": "If a normal woman had a colorblind father, what would her genotype be? (XB = normal vision, Xb = colorblind)", "options": ["XbXb", "XBY", "XbY", "XBXb", "XBXB"], "answer": 3, "keywords": ["genotype", "colorblind", "x-linked", "carrier"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-4-q20", "unit": 9, "question": "Vines in the rainforest must first grow towards a tree before growing up a tree towards the sun. What type of growth movement would be most useful in the initial growth of the vine?", "options": ["Negative phototropism", "Positive phototropism", "Positive gravitropism", "Negative gravitropism", "Positive thigmotropism"], "answer": 0, "keywords": ["vines", "rainforest", "growth", "negative phototropism", "positive phototropism", "positive gravitropism", "negative gravitropism", "positive thigmotropism", "skototropism"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-5-q1", "unit": 8, "question": "Which of the following is the best description of resource partitioning?", "options": ["Ecological succession reaches a climax community when all niches have been filled.", "Species survival is best achieved when prey species are changed regularly.", "The superior species will survive due to competitive exclusion.", "The division of limited resources by two or more species leads to successful coexistence.", "Two species can coevolve and share the same niche."], "answer": 3, "keywords": ["resource partitioning", "ecological succession", "climax community", "niches", "prey", "competitive exclusion", "coexistence", "coevolve"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-5-q3", "unit": 6, "question": "Which of the following is NOT part of Darwin's Theory of Natural Selection?", "options": ["More organisms are born than can survive.", "Organisms struggle for survival.", "Some organisms possess traits that make them better suited for their survival in their environment.", "Organisms can develop beneficial traits during their lifetime that they pass to their offspring.", "Variations exist between organisms within a species."], "answer": 3, "keywords": ["natural selection", "darwin", "survival", "environment", "beneficial traits", "offspring", "variations", "lamarckism"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-5-q4", "unit": 5, "question": "What fraction of offspring will be homozygous recessive for both traits in a cross between an individual that is heterozygous for both traits and an individual that is homozygous recessive for both traits?", "options": ["9/16", "4/16", "3/16", "1/16", "0"], "answer": 1, "keywords": ["offspring", "homozygous recessive", "heterozygous", "dihybrid cross", "test cross", "punnett square"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-5-q5", "unit": 9, "question": "The medulla oblongata responds to levels of ________ in the blood to regulate the respiratory rate.", "options": ["CO2", "O2", "CO", "H+", "Glucose"], "answer": 0, "keywords": ["medulla oblongata", "blood", "respiratory rate", "carbon dioxide", "co2", "homeostasis"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-5-q6", "unit": 10, "question": "Diseases like scrapie and bovine spongiform encephalopathy are due to prions which are", "options": ["infectious RNA fragments.", "viral DNA that incorporated itself in the cell's genome.", "transposons that moved into a gene, inactivating it.", "bacteria that are found in contaminated soil.", "misfolded versions of normal brain proteins."], "answer": 4, "keywords": ["scrapie", "bovine spongiform encephalopathy", "prions", "rna", "viral dna", "genome", "transposons", "bacteria", "proteins"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-5-q7", "unit": 10, "question": "When an infected mosquito bites a person, the malarial parasite enters the bloodstream and travels to the ________ where it can remain dormant for a year.", "options": ["brain", "liver", "spleen", "pancreas", "bone marrow"], "answer": 1, "keywords": ["mosquito", "malarial parasite", "bloodstream", "dormant", "liver", "plasmodium"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-5-q11", "unit": 9, "question": "Which of the following animals uses the greatest percentage of their daily energy expenditures to maintain homeostasis?", "options": ["a salamander in a cave", "a saltwater fish", "a snake in a temperate forest", "a scorpion in the desert", "a bird in the rainforest"], "answer": 4, "keywords": ["energy expenditures", "homeostasis", "salamander", "fish", "snake", "scorpion", "bird", "endotherm", "ectotherm"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-5-q12", "unit": 5, "question": "A transgenic organism", "options": ["is the result of a sperm from one organism fertilizing the egg from a different organism.", "has chromosomes that are the result of crossing-over.", "contains genes from another organism.", "has a genetic mutation that leads to disease.", "is sterile due to the presence of an extra chromosome."], "answer": 2, "keywords": ["transgenic organism", "sperm", "fertilizing", "egg", "chromosomes", "crossing-over", "genes", "genetic mutation"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-5-q13", "unit": 9, "question": "A patient has surgery to remove his seminal vesicles. What effect will this have on his reproductive system?", "options": ["Sperm survival rate will decrease due to a lack of nutrients.", "Sperm production will be decreased.", "Sperm will not mature and develop a tail for locomotion.", "The patient will be sterile, because sperm will be unable to exit the body.", "The volume of semen will be increased to counteract the loss in sperm numbers."], "answer": 0, "keywords": ["seminal vesicles", "reproductive system", "sperm", "nutrients", "semen"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-5-q14", "unit": 9, "question": "The function of the digestive system is to break down food and absorb the nutrients. Most of these nutrients are absorbed in the", "options": ["pancreas.", "stomach.", "esophagus.", "small intestine.", "large intestine."], "answer": 3, "keywords": ["digestive system", "nutrients", "pancreas", "stomach", "esophagus", "small intestine", "large intestine"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-5-q15", "unit": 1, "question": "Penicillin kills bacteria by preventing cell wall formation in newly formed cells, causing them to burst. This indicates that the bacterial cells live in a(n)", "options": ["medium high in salt content.", "hypotonic medium.", "hypertonic medium.", "isotonic medium.", "medium with a lower osmotic potential than the cell."], "answer": 1, "keywords": ["penicillin", "bacteria", "cell wall", "hypotonic", "hypertonic", "isotonic", "osmotic potential"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-5-q16", "unit": 3, "question": "In the light dependent reactions of photosynthesis, what is the first event that occurs after a chlorophyll molecule absorbs a photon?", "options": ["A water molecule is split.", "Carbon dioxide is reduced.", "An electron is boosted to a higher energy level.", "A photon is transferred to NADPH.", "ATP is regenerated."], "answer": 2, "keywords": ["light dependent reactions", "photosynthesis", "chlorophyll", "photon", "water molecule", "carbon dioxide", "electron", "nadph", "atp"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-5-q17", "unit": 2, "question": "Movement of the chromosomes during anaphase would be most affected by a drug that", "options": ["prevents elongation of microtubules.", "prevents shortening of microtubules.", "prevents condensation of chromatin into chromosomes.", "reduces cyclin concentrations.", "increases cyclin concentrations."], "answer": 1, "keywords": ["chromosomes", "anaphase", "microtubules", "chromatin", "cyclin"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-5-q19", "unit": 4, "question": "Variations between organisms of the same species are due to", "options": ["number of bases in a codon.", "the percentages of each biomolecule in the cells.", "sequence of nitrogenous bases in DNA.", "total number of proteins in the cells.", "order of the ribosomes on the endoplasmic reticulum."], "answer": 2, "keywords": ["variations", "species", "codon", "biomolecule", "nitrogenous bases", "dna", "proteins", "ribosomes", "endoplasmic reticulum"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-5-q20", "unit": 1, "question": "The active site is the region of an enzyme that", "options": ["binds with noncompetitive inhibitors.", "is inhibited by the binding of a coenzyme.", "binds with the substrate.", "increases the activation energy of the reaction.", "produces the energy required for the reaction."], "answer": 2, "keywords": ["active site", "enzyme", "noncompetitive inhibitors", "coenzyme", "substrate", "activation energy"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-6-q2", "unit": 6, "question": "Organisms that live on islands are often closely related to organisms on the nearest mainland. However, some differences between the groups are observed. This is evidence that", "options": ["convergent evolution is occurring.", "the two groups of organisms are descended from common ancestors.", "the two groups have identical gene pools, resulting in similarities.", "the island and the mainland are similar environments.", "the islands were originally part of the continent."], "answer": 1, "keywords": ["islands", "mainland", "evolution", "common ancestors", "gene pools", "biogeography"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-6-q4", "unit": 5, "question": "In sheep, black wool is recessive to white wool. In a certain flock of sheep, 3 percent of the population has black wool. Assume that the population is in Hardy-Weinberg equilibrium. What is the frequency of the white wool allele?", "options": ["0.03", "0.17", "0.83", "0.97", "0.98"], "answer": 2, "keywords": ["sheep", "black wool", "white wool", "recessive", "hardy-weinberg", "allele frequency", "population genetics"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-6-q5", "unit": 1, "question": "Which of the following is true of unsaturated fats?", "options": ["Unsaturated fats are found only in animals.", "Unsaturated fats have double bonds in the carbon chains of their fatty acids.", "Unsaturated fats are usually solid at room temperature.", "Unsaturated fats contain more hydrogen atoms per carbon than saturated fats.", "Unsaturated fats contain a sulfhydryl group, but saturated fats do not."], "answer": 1, "keywords": ["unsaturated fats", "double bonds", "carbon chains", "fatty acids", "saturated fats", "hydrogen atoms", "biochemistry"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-6-q6", "unit": 6, "question": "One of the driving factors of evolution is the genetic diversity found in the individuals of a population. The greatest source of this genetic variation is", "options": ["genetic recombination due to crossing over in meiosis.", "mistakes made in the translation of structural genes.", "mistakes in the 3D structure of proteins.", "the unique codes between species for the translation from codon to amino acid.", "the failure of introns to be removed from the final mRNA transcript."], "answer": 0, "keywords": ["evolution", "genetic diversity", "variation", "genetic recombination", "crossing over", "meiosis", "structural genes", "translation"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-6-q8", "unit": 2, "question": "What is the difference between a human cell in prophase of mitosis and in prophase I of meiosis?", "options": ["Only cells in mitosis use kinetochores.", "Cells in prophase I have twice as many chromosomes as those in prophase of mitosis.", "Cells in prophase I have half as many chromosomes as those in prophase of mitosis.", "In meiosis, synapsis of homologous chromosomes occurs during prophase I.", "Crossing-over occurs during mitotic prophase, but not in meiosis."], "answer": 3, "keywords": ["mitosis", "meiosis", "prophase", "prophase i", "kinetochores", "chromosomes", "synapsis", "homologous chromosomes", "crossing-over"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-6-q9", "unit": 3, "question": "The function of accessory pigments in photosynthesis is to", "options": ["produce glucose.", "split water.", "reduce carbon dioxide.", "absorb photons.", "catalyze the oxidation of water."], "answer": 3, "keywords": ["accessory pigments", "photosynthesis", "glucose", "carbon dioxide", "photons", "oxidation", "chlorophyll"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-6-q10", "unit": 7, "question": "Which of the following would be the best outgroup for a phylogenetic tree of cats?", "options": ["jaguar", "tiger", "fox", "leopard", "domesticated cat"], "answer": 2, "keywords": ["outgroup", "phylogenetic tree", "cats", "jaguar", "tiger", "fox", "leopard", "taxonomy"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-6-q11", "unit": 10, "question": "Which of the following is the best explanation for the fact that an individual who has a herpes virus cold sore will continue to experience cold sore flare-ups for life?", "options": ["The herpes virus lives in the bloodstream of the infected person for their entire life.", "The individual is infected by a different strain of herpes virus each time a flare-up occurs.", "The individual is reinfected by the same strain of herpes virus, causing new cold sores", "The cold sores are the result of a mutation in the skin cells caused by the initial infection by the herpes virus.", "The herpes viral DNA is incorporated into the genome of the affected skin cells, becoming active periodically."], "answer": 4, "keywords": ["herpes virus", "cold sore", "bloodstream", "mutation", "viral dna", "genome", "lysogenic cycle", "latency"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-6-q12", "unit": 4, "question": "The anticodon of a particular tRNA molecule is", "options": ["the part of tRNA that binds to the specific amino acid it carries.", "complementary to the corresponding mRNA codon in the transcript.", "complementary to the corresponding codon in rRNA.", "responsible for the three-dimensional structure of the tRNA molecule.", "a catalyst for the reaction that produces the growing amino acid chain."], "answer": 1, "keywords": ["anticodon", "trna", "amino acid", "complementary", "mrna", "codon", "translation"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-6-q13", "unit": 9, "question": "The ________ senses or hears vibrations in amphibians like the frog.", "options": ["nictitating membrane", "tympanic membrane", "external ear", "swim bladder", "lateral line"], "answer": 1, "keywords": ["vibrations", "amphibians", "frog", "nictitating membrane", "tympanic membrane", "swim bladder", "lateral line", "anatomy"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-6-q14", "unit": 8, "question": "The amount of chemical energy in consumers' food that is converted to their own new biomass during a given time period is called", "options": ["biomass assimilation.", "standing crop.", "biomagnification.", "primary production.", "secondary production."], "answer": 4, "keywords": ["chemical energy", "consumers", "biomass", "assimilation", "biomagnification", "primary production", "secondary production", "ecology"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-6-q16", "unit": 9, "question": "Which of the following is an endocrine gland?", "options": ["prostate gland", "sebaceous gland", "mammary gland", "salivary gland", "thyroid gland"], "answer": 4, "keywords": ["endocrine gland", "prostate", "sebaceous", "mammary", "salivary", "thyroid", "hormones"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-6-q18", "unit": 4, "question": "Transcription of the structural genes in an inducible operon", "options": ["is controlled by regulatory genes located in a nearby region of the genome.", "starts when the pathway's substrate is present.", "starts when the pathway's product is present.", "stops when the pathway's product is present.", "occurs continuously."], "answer": 1, "keywords": ["transcription", "structural genes", "inducible operon", "regulatory genes", "genome", "substrate", "gene regulation"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-6-q19", "unit": 8, "question": "Species richness will increase as", "options": ["community size decreases.", "depth increases in the marine environment.", "altitude increases.", "the community's location is closer to the equator.", "the distance of the island from the mainland increases."], "answer": 3, "keywords": ["species richness", "community", "marine", "altitude", "equator", "island", "biodiversity"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-6-q20", "unit": 4, "question": "When scientists first inserted an unmodified mammalian gene into a bacterial chromosome, they had difficulty getting the mammalian gene expressed by the bacteria. The primary reason for this difficulty is that", "options": ["prokaryotes use a different genetic code than eukaryotes.", "bacteria translate RNA genes only.", "bacteria cannot remove eukaryotic introns.", "bacterial RNA polymerase cannot make mRNA complementary to mammalian DNA.", "bacterial DNA is not found in a membrane-bounded nucleus, so eukaryotic DNA excised itself from the bacterial DNA."], "answer": 2, "keywords": ["mammalian gene", "bacterial chromosome", "prokaryotes", "eukaryotes", "introns", "rna polymerase", "gene expression", "biotechnology"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-7-q1", "unit": 10, "question": "Which of the following is NOT an opportunistic infection or disease that commonly affects AIDS patients?", "options": ["Cancer", "Tuberculosis", "Rheumatoid arthritis", "Herpes simplex", "Candidiasis (thrush)"], "answer": 2, "keywords": ["opportunistic infection", "aids", "cancer", "tuberculosis", "rheumatoid arthritis", "herpes simplex", "candidiasis", "thrush"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-7-q2", "unit": 7, "question": "The genome is", "options": ["all of the alleles of all of the genes found in a population.", "all the genetic diseases that are found in a population.", "all of the genes found on the chromosomes of every organism of every species in an area.", "all of the genes on the chromosomes of an organism.", "all of the genes that are unique to a species."], "answer": 3, "keywords": ["genome", "alleles", "genes", "population", "chromosomes", "organism", "species"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-7-q4", "unit": 5, "question": "In a dihybrid cross, a woman who is recessive for both traits marries a man who is heterozygous for both traits. What is the likelihood that their first child will be recessive for both traits?", "options": ["9/16", "3/16", "1/16", "1/2", "1/4"], "answer": 4, "keywords": ["dihybrid cross", "recessive", "heterozygous", "punnett square", "traits", "offspring"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-7-q5", "unit": 1, "question": "Which of the following is NOT true of plasmid DNA?", "options": ["Plasmids are found naturally in most eukaryotic cells.", "Plasmids often contain genes for antibiotic resistance.", "Plasmids are small circular pieces of DNA.", "Plasmids are replicated independently of the main chromosome.", "Plasmids can be used to transfer foreign genes to a cell in genetic engineering."], "answer": 0, "keywords": ["plasmid dna", "eukaryotic", "antibiotic resistance", "circular dna", "replication", "chromosome", "genetic engineering"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-7-q6", "unit": 3, "question": "In plants, glucose is produced during photosynthesis. Which reactant of photosynthesis provides the oxygen atoms that are found in this glucose that is produced?", "options": ["Oxygen gas", "Water", "Carbon dioxide", "Carbohydrates", "NADPH"], "answer": 2, "keywords": ["glucose", "photosynthesis", "reactant", "oxygen atoms", "water", "carbon dioxide", "nadph"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-7-q7", "unit": 8, "question": "Carrying capacity", "options": ["remains constant over time for a population.", "is the maximum birth rate for a population.", "is the percentage of available resources consumed within a habitat.", "is unlikely to be reached in a marine environment due to the vastness of the ocean.", "is the maximum population size that a particular environment can support at a given time."], "answer": 4, "keywords": ["carrying capacity", "population", "birth rate", "habitat", "marine environment", "environment"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-7-q8", "unit": 5, "question": "78% of a population has the dominant trait. If the population is in Hardy Weinberg equilibrium, what is the frequency of the dominant allele?", "options": ["0.22", "0.47", "0.53", "0.28", "0.50"], "answer": 2, "keywords": ["population", "dominant trait", "hardy weinberg", "allele frequency", "dominant allele"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-7-q9", "unit": 1, "question": "The blastula is a stage in the development of an embryo that consists of a", "options": ["solid ball of cells", "hollow ball of cells.", "flat sheet of cells.", "folded sheet of cells.", "single diploid cell."], "answer": 1, "keywords": ["blastula", "embryo", "solid ball", "hollow ball", "cells", "diploid"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-7-q11", "unit": 1, "question": "If the pH of the liver is 7 and the pH of the pancreas is 8, then", "options": ["the concentration of H+ ions is tenfold higher in the pancreas than in the liver.", "the concentration of H+ ions is tenfold higher in the liver than in the pancreas.", "the concentration of H+ ions in the liver is 7/8 the concentration in the pancreas.", "the concentration of H+ ions in the liver is 8/7 the concentration in the pancreas.", "the pancreas is more acidic than the liver."], "answer": 1, "keywords": ["ph", "liver", "pancreas", "h+ ions", "concentration", "acidic"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-7-q12", "unit": 6, "question": "Which of the following is an example of cryptic coloration?", "options": ["Colorful red, yellow and black bands on the venomous coral snake", "Brown or gray color of tree bark", "Markings of a viceroy butterfly's wings that are similar to the bitter tasting monarch butterfly's", "Color of an insect-pollinated flower's petals", "“Walking stick” insect that resembles a twig"], "answer": 4, "keywords": ["cryptic coloration", "camouflage", "coral snake", "viceroy butterfly", "monarch butterfly", "walking stick", "insect"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-7-q13", "unit": 1, "question": "A weak attraction that can form between any atoms or molecules that are close to each other is a(n)", "options": ["ionic bond.", "polar covalent bond.", "nonpolar covalent bond.", "Van der Waal force.", "hydrogen bond."], "answer": 3, "keywords": ["attraction", "atoms", "molecules", "ionic bond", "polar covalent", "nonpolar covalent", "van der waal force", "hydrogen bond"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-7-q14", "unit": 9, "question": "A plant that is placed in a sunny window will grow towards the light in a plant response called phototropism. Which of the following statements is true regarding phototropism?", "options": ["Gibberellic acid causes cell division in the plant cells on the side of the stem away from the light.", "Ethylene causes the bending of plant cells in the stem.", "Auxin causes cell division and elongation in the cells on the dark side of the stem.", "Auxin causes a decrease in cell division on the side of the stem exposed to light.", "Cytokinin causes cell division in the tip of the plant stem."], "answer": 2, "keywords": ["phototropism", "gibberellic acid", "ethylene", "auxin", "cell division", "elongation", "cytokinin"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-7-q15", "unit": 9, "question": "Two communicating neurons connect at a", "options": ["synapse.", "axon.", "dendrite.", "cell body.", "glia."], "answer": 0, "keywords": ["neurons", "synapse", "axon", "dendrite", "cell body", "glia"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-7-q17", "unit": 3, "question": "Which of the following statements is true for exergonic reactions?", "options": ["Exergonic reactions require an input of energy for the reaction to occur.", "The products have more free energy than the reactants.", "The products have less free energy than the reactants.", "The reactants are always completely converted into products.", "Exergonic reactions have a positive standard Gibbs free energy."], "answer": 2, "keywords": ["exergonic reactions", "energy", "free energy", "reactants", "products", "gibbs free energy"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-7-q18", "unit": 6, "question": "Organisms living on an island are often found to have both similarities and differences from organisms found on the nearest mainland. This is evidence that", "options": ["island forms and mainland forms descended from common ancestors.", "the same organisms live in similar environments throughout the world.", "the islands were originally part of the continent.", "convergent evolution is occurring.", "the populations have identical gene pools."], "answer": 0, "keywords": ["island", "mainland", "common ancestors", "evolution", "environments", "gene pools"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-7-q19", "unit": 2, "question": "Eukaryotic cells produce daughter cells by mitosis and gametes by meiosis. Which of the following does not contribute to genetic variation in eukaryotic cells?", "options": ["anaphase of mitosis", "anaphase I of meiosis", "mutations during DNA replication", "random assortment of egg and sperm union during fertilization", "crossing over in homologous chromosomes"], "answer": 0, "keywords": ["eukaryotic", "mitosis", "meiosis", "genetic variation", "anaphase", "mutations", "dna replication", "fertilization", "crossing over"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-8-q1", "unit": 2, "question": "How is the lytic cycle different from the lysogenic cycle?", "options": ["The genome of all lytic viruses is comprised of RNA, not DNA.", "The lytic cycle contains the formation of a prophage.", "In the lysogenic cycle, the virus remains dormant until activated.", "The lysogenic cycle utilizes the host cell to manufacture new viruses soon after viral entry into the host cell.", "Replication never occurs in the lysogenic cycle."], "answer": 2, "keywords": ["lytic cycle", "lysogenic cycle", "virus", "prophage", "dormant", "replication", "host cell"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-8-q4", "unit": 5, "question": "A man who has type O blood marries a woman with homozygous type A blood. What is the phenotypic ratio of the offspring for a cross between these individuals?", "options": ["all type O", "all type A", "1 type A: 1 type O", "3 type A: 1 type O", "3 type O: 1 type A"], "answer": 1, "keywords": ["blood type", "homozygous", "phenotypic ratio", "offspring", "cross", "inheritance", "punnett square"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-8-q5", "unit": 8, "question": "The role of detrivores in the ecosystem is to", "options": ["secrete enzymes for use by decomposers in the breakdown of decaying matter.", "ensure that the predator population does not exceed the limits of prey availability.", "synthesize carbohydrates for primary producers.", "break down dead and decaying material from all trophic levels to recycle nutrients.", "convert nitrogen compounds in the atmosphere into a form usable by primary producers."], "answer": 3, "keywords": ["detrivores", "ecosystem", "decomposers", "trophic levels", "nutrients", "recycling"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-8-q6", "unit": 7, "question": "Scientists believe that the first cells were heterotrophs. Eventually, some cells evolved the ability to make their own food through photosynthesis. The rise of autotrophs is signaled by an increase in the concentration of ________ in the atmosphere.", "options": ["N2", "O2", "CO2", "H2O", "H+"], "answer": 1, "keywords": ["heterotrophs", "autotrophs", "photosynthesis", "atmosphere", "n2", "o2", "co2", "h2o"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-8-q7", "unit": 5, "question": "A transgenic organism", "options": ["contains the reproductive organs of both genders at birth.", "is the result of crossing over during gamete development.", "contains genes from another organism.", "has a genetic mutation that leads to a genetic disease.", "contains an extra sex chromosome, so it is sterile."], "answer": 2, "keywords": ["transgenic organism", "genes", "genetic mutation", "chromosome", "recombinant dna"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-8-q8", "unit": 4, "question": "The substitution of a single base pair in the DNA code may have little effect on the protein produced for all of the following reasons EXCEPT:", "options": ["A change in one amino acid in the protein produced will not affect its function.", "The wobble phenomenon could result in no change in the amino acid translated.", "The amino acid that is substituted may have similar properties to the one that it replaced.", "Most amino acids have several possible DNA codons, so a change in the genetic code may not change the amino acid translated.", "A missense mutation may occur in part of the protein that is not critical to its functioning."], "answer": 0, "keywords": ["substitution", "dna code", "protein", "amino acid", "wobble phenomenon", "codons", "missense mutation"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-8-q9", "unit": 9, "question": "You measured blood hormone levels before and after eating a carbohydrate heavy meal. How do the post-meal levels of these hormones compare to pre-meal levels?", "options": ["higher insulin, lower glucagon", "lower insulin, lower glucagon", "higher insulin, higher glucagon", "lower insulin, higher glucagon", "lower insulin, no change in glucagon"], "answer": 0, "keywords": ["hormone", "carbohydrate", "insulin", "glucagon", "homeostasis", "blood glucose"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-8-q10", "unit": 9, "question": "The human body temperature is regulated by the", "options": ["liver.", "thyroid gland.", "hypothalamus.", "medulla oblongata.", "subcutaneous layer of skin."], "answer": 2, "keywords": ["body temperature", "hypothalamus", "homeostasis", "regulation"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-8-q11", "unit": 1, "question": "Chlorine ions are the second most abundant ion in the human body. They have many important functions including maintaining blood pressure and blood volume and stimulating the action of nerve and muscle cells. Chlorine has mass number of 35 and an atomic number of 17. How many electrons would a chloride ion have?", "options": ["34", "33", "16", "17", "18"], "answer": 4, "keywords": ["chlorine", "ion", "electrons", "mass number", "atomic number", "chloride"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-8-q12", "unit": 9, "question": "Which embryonic germ layer develops into the skeletal and circulatory systems of animals?", "options": ["Ectoderm", "Mesoderm", "Periderm", "Protoderm", "Endoderm"], "answer": 1, "keywords": ["embryonic germ layer", "skeletal system", "circulatory system", "ectoderm", "mesoderm", "endoderm"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-8-q13", "unit": 7, "question": "Arthropods are classified based on the number and structure of their", "options": ["body segments and appendages.", "eyes and wings.", "muscles and bones.", "hearts and lungs.", "mouthparts and excretory organs."], "answer": 0, "keywords": ["arthropods", "classification", "body segments", "appendages"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-8-q14", "unit": 1, "question": "The functional group that can cause an organic molecule to act as a base is", "options": ["-CH3", "-OH", "-SH", "-OPO3", "-NH2"], "answer": 4, "keywords": ["functional group", "organic molecule", "base", "amino group", "nh2"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-8-q15", "unit": 10, "question": "Which of the following is a method of bacterial defense against viral infection?", "options": ["Episomes that inactivate the viral DNA", "Production of antibiotics by the bacteria", "Restriction nucleases that cut up foreign DNA", "R plasmids that contain genes for resistance", "Reverse transcriptase that translates the viral code into DNA"], "answer": 2, "keywords": ["bacterial defense", "viral infection", "restriction nucleases", "foreign dna", "crispr"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-8-q16", "unit": 6, "question": "Over time, the movement of people on Earth has steadily increased. This has altered the course of human evolution by increasing", "options": ["nonrandom mating.", "geographic isolation.", "genetic drift.", "gene flow.", "the bottleneck effect."], "answer": 3, "keywords": ["evolution", "nonrandom mating", "geographic isolation", "genetic drift", "gene flow", "bottleneck effect"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-8-q17", "unit": 3, "question": "Which of the following is an important difference between light-dependent and light-independent reactions of photosynthesis?", "options": ["The light-dependent reactions occur only during the day; the light-independent reactions occur only during the night.", "The light-dependent reactions occur in the cytoplasm; the light-independent reactions occur in chloroplasts.", "The light-dependent reactions produce ATP and NADPH; the light-independent reactions use ATP and NADPH in the production of carbohydrates.", "The light-dependent reactions utilize CO2 and H2O the light-independent reactions produce CO2 and H2O.", "The light dependent reactions produce O2; the light independent reactions produce CO2"], "answer": 2, "keywords": ["light-dependent", "light-independent", "photosynthesis", "atp", "nadph", "carbohydrates", "chloroplasts"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-8-q18", "unit": 2, "question": "Which of the following enzymes is NOT involved in DNA replication?", "options": ["Rubisco", "Helicase", "Primase", "DNA ligase", "DNA polymerase"], "answer": 0, "keywords": ["enzymes", "dna replication", "rubisco", "helicase", "primase", "dna ligase", "dna polymerase"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-8-q19", "unit": 7, "question": "In order to act as a molecular clock a gene needs to", "options": ["have a large number of base pairs.", "have a larger proportion of exons than introns.", "have a reliable average rate of mutation.", "have evolved recently.", "be affected strongly by natural selection."], "answer": 2, "keywords": ["molecular clock", "gene", "mutation rate", "evolution"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-8-q20", "unit": 4, "question": "An mRNA molecule being actively translated in the cytoplasm would have all of the following EXCEPT", "options": ["a poly-A tail.", "a 5' cap.", "exons.", "introns.", "RNA nucleotides."], "answer": 3, "keywords": ["mrna", "translation", "cytoplasm", "poly-a tail", "5' cap", "exons", "introns"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-9-q1", "unit": 10, "question": "Which of the following is not a vector borne disease?", "options": ["Pneumonia", "Malaria", "Zika", "Typhus", "Lyme disease"], "answer": 0, "keywords": ["vector-borne", "disease", "pneumonia", "malaria", "zika", "typhus", "lyme disease"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-9-q2", "unit": 4, "question": "The amount of protein made from a given mRNA molecule depends partly on", "options": ["the rate at which the mRNA is degraded.", "the percentage of DNA that is methylated.", "the number of exons present in the mRNA.", "the number of histones in the nucleosome bundle.", "the concentration of transcription factors in the cytoplasm."], "answer": 0, "keywords": ["protein", "mrna", "degradation", "dna", "methylation", "exons", "histones", "nucleosome", "transcription factors", "cytoplasm"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-9-q3", "unit": 8, "question": "Which of the following is primarily responsible for limiting the number of trophic levels in most ecosystems?", "options": ["The high percentage of omnivores limits the number of species that an ecosystem can support.", "Predators keep population sizes low.", "Abiotic factors in the ecosystem recycle nutrients into the ecosystem at a rate that is too slow to support many trophic levels.", "Most ecosystems do not have enough species variety at the producer trophic level.", "Energy transfer between trophic levels is in almost all cases less than 20% efficient."], "answer": 4, "keywords": ["trophic levels", "ecosystems", "omnivores", "predators", "abiotic factors", "nutrients", "producers", "energy transfer", "efficiency"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-9-q4", "unit": 5, "question": "In some flowers, the trait for petal color shows incomplete dominance. (R = red petals, W = white petals) If a pink flowered plant is crossed with a white flowered plant, what will the phenotypic ratio of the offspring be?", "options": ["3 red: 1 white", "1 red: 2 pink: 1 white", "2 red: 2 pink", "2 pink: 2 white", "2 red: 2 white"], "answer": 3, "keywords": ["incomplete dominance", "petal", "color", "phenotypic ratio", "cross", "offspring", "punnett square"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-9-q6", "unit": 1, "question": "Plants store most of their energy as", "options": ["starch.", "glycogen.", "glucose.", "sucrose.", "cellulose."], "answer": 0, "keywords": ["plants", "energy", "storage", "starch", "glycogen", "glucose", "sucrose", "cellulose"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-9-q7", "unit": 5, "question": "In a population of 100 individuals, 78 individuals have the dominant trait. If the population is in Hardy Weinberg equilibrium, what is the frequency of the recessive allele?", "options": ["0.22", "0.47", "0.53", "0.28", "0.50"], "answer": 1, "keywords": ["hardy-weinberg", "equilibrium", "dominant", "trait", "frequency", "recessive", "allele"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-9-q9", "unit": 2, "question": "A plant cell has 6 chromosomes at the end of mitosis. How many chromosomes would it have in the G2 phase of its next cell cycle?", "options": ["3", "6", "9", "12", "24"], "answer": 3, "keywords": ["chromosomes", "mitosis", "g2 phase", "cell cycle", "dna replication"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-9-q10", "unit": 4, "question": "A mutation occurs in the regulatory gene of a repressible operon causing it to become nonfunctional. This would result in", "options": ["the structural gene being continuously transcribed.", "continuous synthesis of the inducer.", "accumulation of large quantities of the substrate.", "the inability to remove the repressor from the operator.", "excessive synthesis of the catabolic activator protein."], "answer": 0, "keywords": ["mutation", "regulatory gene", "repressible operon", "structural gene", "transcription", "inducer", "substrate", "repressor", "operator", "catabolic activator protein"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-9-q11", "unit": 7, "question": "Which of the following cannot lead to genetic variation in bacteria?", "options": ["Mutation", "Transformation", "Binary fission", "Transduction", "Conjugation"], "answer": 2, "keywords": ["genetic variation", "bacteria", "mutation", "transformation", "binary fission", "transduction", "conjugation"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-9-q12", "unit": 9, "question": "An agricultural company ships ripe fruit to an overseas market. Which chemical needs to be eliminated from the shipping environment to ensure the quality of fruit upon arrival?", "options": ["CO2", "cytokinins", "ethylene", "auxin", "gibberellic acids"], "answer": 2, "keywords": ["fruit", "ripening", "hormones", "co2", "cytokinins", "ethylene", "auxin", "gibberellic acids"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-9-q13", "unit": 3, "question": "Enzymes catalyze reactions by", "options": ["lowering the ΔG of the reaction.", "changing the equilibrium of the reaction.", "lowering the activation energy of the reaction.", "providing energy to speed up the reaction.", "by transforming a reaction from an endergonic reaction to an exergonic reaction."], "answer": 2, "keywords": ["enzymes", "catalysis", "gibbs free energy", "equilibrium", "activation energy", "endergonic", "exergonic"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-9-q14", "unit": 9, "question": "A major difference between active and passive immunity is that active immunity", "options": ["lasts only a few months.", "only occurs through vaccinations.", "is the transfer of antibodies from the mother across the placenta.", "involves direct exposure to a pathogen or other foreign organism.", "does not require the production of antibodies."], "answer": 3, "keywords": ["active immunity", "passive immunity", "vaccinations", "antibodies", "placenta", "pathogen"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-9-q15", "unit": 6, "question": "Which of the following conditions would not cause a change in frequency of a specific allele in a population?", "options": ["Selection against the recessive phenotype", "Selection against the dominant phenotype", "Genetic drift", "Random mating in a large population", "Gene flow"], "answer": 3, "keywords": ["allele frequency", "selection", "recessive phenotype", "dominant phenotype", "genetic drift", "random mating", "gene flow", "hardy-weinberg"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-9-q16", "unit": 9, "question": "The compound eyes of insects", "options": ["are composed of many lenses contained within independent photoreception units.", "provide a narrow field of view.", "are not effective at detecting movement.", "are composed of one lens contained within the ocelli.", "produce an image that is more detailed than what humans see."], "answer": 0, "keywords": ["compound eyes", "insects", "lenses", "photoreception", "ocelli"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-9-q17", "unit": 2, "question": "Which of the following is NOT true of reverse transcriptase?", "options": ["It is a virus produced enzyme.", "It catalyzes the synthesis of a complementary strand of DNA from the viral RNA template.", "It catalyzes the synthesis of viral DNA from the mRNA of the host cell.", "It is found in retroviruses.", "It catalyzes the synthesis of DNA from RNA which is an exception to the Central Dogma of molecular biology."], "answer": 2, "keywords": ["reverse transcriptase", "virus", "enzyme", "dna synthesis", "rna template", "mrna", "retroviruses", "central dogma"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-9-q18", "unit": 3, "question": "Photosynthesis is a metabolic process used by some autotrophs to convert light energy into chemical energy. Which of the following would NOT reduce the product yield of photosynthesis?", "options": ["Increased photorespiration", "Fewer Calvin Cycle enzymes", "Reduced carbon dioxide concentrations in the air spaces of the leaf", "High concentrations of oxygen in the air spaces in the leaf", "Increased frequency of stomata openings"], "answer": 4, "keywords": ["photosynthesis", "autotrophs", "light energy", "chemical energy", "photorespiration", "calvin cycle", "enzymes", "carbon dioxide", "oxygen", "stomata"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-9-q19", "unit": 2, "question": "Programmed cell death is called", "options": ["metastasis.", "apoptosis.", "mitotic termination.", "predetermination.", "degradation."], "answer": 1, "keywords": ["cell death", "apoptosis", "metastasis", "mitotic termination", "degradation"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-9-q20", "unit": 9, "question": "The advantage of excreting waste as urea rather than ammonia is that", "options": ["urea can be exchanged for Na+", "urea requires less water for excretion than ammonia.", "urea is less toxic than ammonia.", "urea does not affect the osmolar gradient.", "Both B and C are advantages."], "answer": 4, "keywords": ["excretion", "waste", "urea", "ammonia", "na+", "toxicity", "osmolar gradient"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-10-q1", "unit": 9, "question": "Which of the following is NOT involved with the human nonspecific defense mechanism?", "options": ["Lysozyme", "Chemokines", "Natural killer cells", "Histamine", "Plasma cells"], "answer": 4, "keywords": ["nonspecific defense", "lysozyme", "chemokines", "natural killer cells", "histamine", "plasma cells"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-10-q2", "unit": 7, "question": "All of the following are the common characteristics of amphibians EXCEPT:", "options": ["life cycle that includes both aquatic and terrestrial phases", "endothermy", "respiration through their skin, lungs, gills at different life stages", "an aquatic egg or larval stage", "all are characteristics"], "answer": 1, "keywords": ["amphibians", "life cycle", "aquatic", "terrestrial", "endothermy", "respiration", "larval stage"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-10-q3", "unit": 10, "question": "Scientist at Leiden University Medical Center successfully engineered living vectors to deliver the malaria vaccine. What living vector did they use?", "options": ["Tick", "Flea", "Mosquito", "Tse-Tse fly", "Sand fly"], "answer": 2, "keywords": ["leiden university", "vectors", "malaria", "vaccine", "tick", "flea", "mosquito", "tse-tse fly", "sand fly"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-10-q4", "unit": 5, "question": "If X^B = normal vision and X^b = colorblind, what is the genotypic ratio of a cross between a homozygous normal female and a colorblind male?", "options": ["All X^B X^b", "2 X^B X^b : 1 X^B Y : 1 X^b Y", "1 X^B X^B : 1 X^B X^b : 1 X^B Y : 1 X^b Y", "1 X^B X^b : 1 X^B Y", "1 X^B X^b : 1 X^b Y"], "answer": 3, "keywords": ["sex-linked", "colorblind", "genotypic ratio", "cross", "punnett square", "homozygous"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-10-q5", "unit": 3, "question": "After strenuous exercise, a muscle cell would contain an increased amount of all of the following EXCEPT", "options": ["Pi", "O2", "CO2", "Lactate", "ADP"], "answer": 1, "keywords": ["muscle cell", "exercise", "pi", "o2", "co2", "lactate", "adp", "cellular respiration"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-10-q6", "unit": 9, "question": "Someone with type A blood makes ______ antibodies.", "options": ["anti-A", "anti-B", "anti-O", "both Anti-B and Anti-A", "no"], "answer": 1, "keywords": ["blood type", "type a", "antibodies", "anti-b"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-10-q7", "unit": 1, "question": "In a nucleosome, the DNA is wrapped around", "options": ["ribosomes.", "histones.", "polymerase molecules.", "plasmids.", "the nucleolus."], "answer": 1, "keywords": ["nucleosome", "dna", "histones", "ribosomes", "polymerase", "plasmids", "nucleolus"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-10-q8", "unit": 8, "question": "Male mice will compete for mates by circling their opponents before the fight begins. This behavior is an example of", "options": ["operant conditioning.", "agonistic behavior.", "habituation.", "imprinting.", "fixed action pattern."], "answer": 1, "keywords": ["mice", "behavior", "operant conditioning", "agonistic behavior", "habituation", "imprinting", "fixed action pattern"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-10-q9", "unit": 1, "question": "Which of the following statements is NOT true of microtubules?", "options": ["Microtubules are made of the protein tubulin.", "Microtubules are involved in cell motility.", "Microtubules are organized by basal bodies or centrioles.", "The spindle fibers of cell division are made of microtubules.", "Microtubules bind cells together at the desmosome."], "answer": 4, "keywords": ["microtubules", "tubulin", "motility", "basal bodies", "centrioles", "spindle fibers", "desmosome"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-10-q10", "unit": 6, "question": "In the phrase \"survival of the fittest\", the term \"fittest\" refers to an organism's", "options": ["physical strength and speed.", "total number of structural genes.", "overall intelligence.", "suitability for its environment.", "rate of gene mutation."], "answer": 3, "keywords": ["survival of the fittest", "natural selection", "genes", "environment", "mutation"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-10-q11", "unit": 2, "question": "Which of the following is true of sister chromatids?", "options": ["They have half the amount of genetic material as the original chromosome.", "They move along spindle fibers towards opposite poles during telophase of mitosis.", "They are formed during prophase.", "They are also called homologous chromosomes.", "They are pairs of identical strands of DNA formed by DNA replication."], "answer": 4, "keywords": ["sister chromatids", "genetic material", "chromosome", "spindle fibers", "mitosis", "telophase", "prophase", "homologous", "dna replication"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-10-q12", "unit": 5, "question": "Scientists can make numerous copies of a specific segment of DNA using a process called", "options": ["gel electrophoresis.", "polymerase chain reaction.", "Southern blot.", "transduction.", "RNA replication."], "answer": 1, "keywords": ["dna", "gel electrophoresis", "polymerase chain reaction", "pcr", "southern blot", "transduction"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-10-q13", "unit": 1, "question": "The DNA of an organism contains 20% cytosine. How much adenine does it contain?", "options": ["10%", "20%", "30%", "40%", "60%"], "answer": 2, "keywords": ["dna", "cytosine", "adenine", "chargaff's rules"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-10-q15", "unit": 1, "question": "When a protein denatures, it", "options": ["loses its primary structure.", "loses its secondary and tertiary structure.", "becomes irreversibly bonded to the nearest identical protein molecule.", "becomes insoluble in the solution.", "breaks down into its individual amino acid components."], "answer": 1, "keywords": ["protein", "denature", "primary structure", "secondary structure", "tertiary structure", "amino acid"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-10-q16", "unit": 8, "question": "According to the theory of island biogeography, species richness would be greatest on an island that is", "options": ["large and close to a mainland.", "small and close to a mainland.", "small and remote.", "large and remote.", "the result of volcanic activity."], "answer": 0, "keywords": ["island biogeography", "species richness", "natural selection"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-10-q17", "unit": 4, "question": "An example of post transcriptional control in gene expression is", "options": ["the removal of introns from the mRNA transcript.", "gene amplification to increase the effect of the gene.", "the addition of methyl groups to cytosine bases in DNA.", "the binding of transcription factors to a promoter region.", "the folding of DNA to limit access to a gene."], "answer": 0, "keywords": ["post transcriptional control", "gene expression", "introns", "mrna", "gene amplification", "methylation", "cytosine", "transcription factors", "promoter"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-10-q18", "unit": 9, "question": "After being formed in a kidney, urine collects in the renal pelvis and drains directly into the ______ to reach the urinary bladder.", "options": ["urethra", "bile duct", "ureter", "ductus venosus", "aorta"], "answer": 2, "keywords": ["kidney", "urine", "renal pelvis", "urinary bladder", "urethra", "bile duct", "ureter", "ductus venosus", "aorta"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-10-q19", "unit": 6, "question": "A species of flowers is pollinated by bees. Its flowers are short and wide which prevents hummingbirds from feeding on its nectar. What type of isolating mechanism is this?", "options": ["Geographic", "Behavioral", "Temporal", "Postzygotic", "Mechanical"], "answer": 4, "keywords": ["pollinated", "bees", "hummingbirds", "nectar", "isolating mechanism", "geographic", "behavioral", "temporal", "postzygotic", "mechanical"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-11-q1", "unit": 1, "question": "The HBB gene in humans provides limited resistance to malaria by affecting red blood cell shape. This gene is also responsible for", "options": ["leukemia.", "pernicious anemia.", "thalassemia.", "sickle cell anemia.", "polycythemia."], "answer": 3, "keywords": ["hbb gene", "malaria", "red blood cell", "leukemia", "pernicious anemia", "thalassemia", "sickle cell anemia", "polycythemia"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-11-q2", "unit": 10, "question": "A patient presented with fever, headache, stiff neck, and nausea. The most likely diagnosis would be", "options": ["tetanus.", "diphtheria.", "anthrax.", "cholera.", "meningitis."], "answer": 4, "keywords": ["fever", "headache", "stiff neck", "nausea", "tetanus", "diphtheria", "anthrax", "cholera", "meningitis"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-11-q4", "unit": 7, "question": "The primary role of the mushroom's underground mycelium is", "options": ["nutrient absorption.", "sexual reproduction.", "asexual reproduction.", "protection.", "nitrogen fixation."], "answer": 0, "keywords": ["mushroom", "mycelium", "nutrient absorption", "sexual reproduction", "asexual reproduction", "nitrogen fixation"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-11-q5", "unit": 5, "question": "In a particular species of flowering plant, the trait for purple flowers is dominant to white flowers and the trait for dwarfism is recessive. A dihybrid plant with purple flowers and normal height is pollinated by a plant that is homozygous for purple petals and heterozygous for normal height. What is the probability that the offspring will be normal height plants with purple flowers?", "options": ["75%", "56%", "25%", "19%", "6%"], "answer": 0, "keywords": ["dihybrid", "dominant", "recessive", "homozygous", "heterozygous", "probability", "offspring", "punnett square"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-11-q6", "unit": 3, "question": "Adenosine triphosphate is the short term, stored energy molecule of the cell. ATP generally energizes a cellular process by", "options": ["binding two monomers together with one of its phosphate groups, forming ADP as a waste product.", "releasing heat during hydrolysis which increases the movement of the reactants.", "acting as an enzyme in the reaction.", "breaking the high energy bonds of the macromolecules.", "coupling the free energy released by ATP hydrolysis to the free energy needed by other reactions."], "answer": 4, "keywords": ["adenosine triphosphate", "atp", "cellular process", "hydrolysis", "free energy", "adp"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-11-q7", "unit": 9, "question": "Endocrine signals are transmitted more slowly than paracrine signals, because", "options": ["the ligands travel greater distances through the bloodstream.", "the ligands move by diffusion through the extracellular matrix.", "the target and signaling cells are closer together.", "the ligands are degraded rapidly and must be replenished frequently.", "the ligands must bind to a transport cell to move through the bloodstream."], "answer": 0, "keywords": ["endocrine", "paracrine", "ligands", "bloodstream", "diffusion", "extracellular matrix"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-11-q8", "unit": 4, "question": "Which of the following is NOT true of translational control of genes in eukaryotes?", "options": ["The life of mRNA is dependent upon the length of its PolyA tail.", "Methylation of the mRNA prevents the binding of the tRNA to the ribosomal complex during translation.", "miRNA protein complexes prevent gene expression by either degrading the target mRNA or by blocking its translation.", "Translational repressors bind to the beginning of mRNA to prevent its binding to the ribosome.", "Ubiquitin can bind to a protein to mark it for degradation, ending its life span."], "answer": 1, "keywords": ["translational control", "eukaryotes", "mrna", "polya tail", "methylation", "trna", "mirna", "ubiquitin"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-11-q9", "unit": 2, "question": "Which of the following statements is NOT true about crossing over?", "options": ["Crossing over is a source of genetic variation.", "Crossing over occurs during prophase II of meiosis.", "Non-sister chromatids exchange genetic material.", "Recombination nodules mediate crossover events.", "Chiasmata form where crossing over occurs."], "answer": 1, "keywords": ["crossing over", "genetic variation", "prophase ii", "meiosis", "non-sister chromatids", "recombination nodules", "chiasmata"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-11-q10", "unit": 8, "question": "A field contains 4000 kilograms of plant material. How many kilograms of carnivore production can be supported by this field?", "options": ["4000", "2000", "400", "40", "4"], "answer": 3, "keywords": ["trophic levels", "biomass", "energy pyramid", "carnivore", "production"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-11-q11", "unit": 10, "question": "Emerging viruses develop when an existing virus", "options": ["spreads to a new host species.", "mutates into a new form or strain.", "has a dramatic increase in incidence or geographic range.", "All of these.", "None of these"], "answer": 3, "keywords": ["emerging viruses", "host species", "mutation", "geographic range"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-11-q12", "unit": 6, "question": "A mutation introduced a new skin color in a lizard population. The frequency of this new allele will increase if", "options": ["the population has only a few color phenotypes.", "the allele for the new trait is dominant.", "the mutation was due to an environmental factor, not human intervention.", "the new allele increases the fitness of the individual.", "the allele first occurs in females rather than in males."], "answer": 3, "keywords": ["mutation", "lizard", "allele frequency", "phenotypes", "fitness", "natural selection"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-11-q13", "unit": 5, "question": "CRISPR-Cas9 was originally discovered as part of a defense mechanism against viruses in", "options": ["bacteria.", "humans.", "fungi.", "chimpanzee.", "mice."], "answer": 0, "keywords": ["crispr-cas9", "defense mechanism", "viruses", "bacteria"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-11-q14", "unit": 3, "question": "The cells in leaves contain both chloroplast and mitochondria. Why do photosynthetic cells contain mitochondria?", "options": ["Mitochondria are vestigial structures in photosynthetic cells.", "In photosynthetic cells, mitochondria complete the light dependent stage and chloroplast complete the light independent stage of photosynthesis.", "In photosynthetic cells, mitochondria complete the light independent stage and chloroplast complete the light dependent stage of photosynthesis.", "Photosynthetic cells need mitochondria to convert the energy from sugar into a form usable by the cell.", "Mitochondria of plants undergo photosynthesis during the day and respiration at night."], "answer": 3, "keywords": ["leaves", "chloroplast", "mitochondria", "photosynthetic", "sugar", "respiration"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-11-q15", "unit": 8, "question": "A scientist is monitoring the concentration of oxygen in a local lake. On a spring day, she collects samples of lake water at 7:00 AM, noon, 5:00 PM, and 2:00 AM. At which time should she see the greatest dissolved oxygen concentration?", "options": ["7:00 AM", "Noon", "5:00 PM", "2:00 AM", "Oxygen concentrations will not change."], "answer": 2, "keywords": ["oxygen", "lake", "dissolved oxygen", "photosynthesis"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-11-q16", "unit": 1, "question": "Which of the following statements about the cytoskeleton is INCORRECT?", "options": ["The cytoskeleton anchors the nucleus and other organelles in place.", "The cytoskeleton is made of three types of fibers: microfilaments (actin filaments), intermediate filaments and microtubules.", "The movement of cilia and flagella relies upon the action of motor proteins on microtubules.", "Transport vesicles of the endomembrane system depend on the cytoskeleton to move through the cell.", "The cytoskeleton creates pores in the plasma membrane for cellular transport."], "answer": 4, "keywords": ["cytoskeleton", "microfilaments", "actin", "intermediate filaments", "microtubules", "cilia", "flagella", "motor proteins", "endomembrane system"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-11-q17", "unit": 9, "question": "The hormone that is produced by the corpus luteum and later by the placenta that is responsible for maintaining a pregnancy is", "options": ["estrogen.", "progesterone.", "luteinizing hormone.", "follicle stimulating hormone.", "human chorionic gonadotropin."], "answer": 1, "keywords": ["hormone", "corpus luteum", "placenta", "pregnancy", "estrogen", "progesterone", "luteinizing hormone", "follicle stimulating hormone", "human chorionic gonadotropin"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-11-q18", "unit": 9, "question": "Growth inhibition in seeds is due to", "options": ["the presence of abscisic acid.", "low concentrations of ethylene.", "high concentrations of gibberellins.", "low concentrations of abscisic acid combined with large concentrations of gibberellins.", "high concentrations of cytokinins combined with lower concentrations of auxin."], "answer": 0, "keywords": ["growth inhibition", "seeds", "abscisic acid", "ethylene", "gibberellins", "cytokinins", "auxin"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-11-q19", "unit": 9, "question": "The atria of the heart will release atrial natriuretic factor when there is a", "options": ["rise in blood pressure.", "drop in blood pressure.", "rise in blood pH.", "drop in blood pH.", "rise in solute concentration in the blood."], "answer": 0, "keywords": ["atria", "heart", "atrial natriuretic factor", "blood pressure", "ph", "solute"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-12-q1", "unit": 10, "question": "Tuberculosis is a bacterial infection that has the greatest effect on the", "options": ["kidneys.", "heart.", "liver.", "brain.", "lungs."], "answer": 4, "keywords": ["tuberculosis", "bacterial infection", "lungs", "kidneys", "heart", "liver", "brain"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-12-q2", "unit": 2, "question": "In colorectal cancer, several genes must be mutated to transform a cell into a cancer cell. Which of the following kinds of genes would you expect to be mutated?", "options": ["Genes coding for enzymes that digest macromolecules in the colon", "Genes involved in control of the cell cycle", "Genes coding for the formation of the receptor proteins in the plasma membrane", "The oncogene that is the cause of all cancers", "Genes found in bacteria that are abundant in the colon"], "answer": 1, "keywords": ["colorectal cancer", "mutation", "cell cycle", "oncogene", "macromolecules", "plasma membrane", "bacteria"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-12-q3", "unit": 9, "question": "Which of the following animals is an osmoregulator but not a thermoregulator?", "options": ["Goldfish", "Jellyfish", "Mouse", "Sparrow", "Starfish"], "answer": 0, "keywords": ["osmoregulator", "thermoregulator", "goldfish", "jellyfish", "mouse", "sparrow", "starfish"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-12-q4", "unit": 3, "question": "A plant cell suffers intercellular damage in which the thylakoid is punctured so that the interior of the thylakoid is no longer separated from the stroma. This damage will have a direct effect on", "options": ["the Calvin Cycle.", "the synthesis of ATP.", "uptake of carbon dioxide by the plant cell.", "the absorption of light energy by the chlorophyll.", "the splitting of water."], "answer": 1, "keywords": ["plant cell", "thylakoid", "stroma", "atp synthesis", "calvin cycle", "carbon dioxide", "chlorophyll", "photophosphorylation"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-12-q5", "unit": 10, "question": "Which of the following is NOT a disease caused by a virus?", "options": ["Smallpox", "Hepatitis", "Measles", "Shingles", "Diphtheria"], "answer": 4, "keywords": ["virus", "disease", "smallpox", "hepatitis", "measles", "shingles", "diphtheria"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-12-q7", "unit": 6, "question": "Over evolutionary time, cave salamanders have lost their eyes. How does the theory of natural selection explain this loss?", "options": ["Natural selection can only explain the development of new traits not the loss of existing traits.", "Any trait that is not used by an individual is not passed to the offspring.", "Harmful mutations caused the loss of eyes forcing the salamanders to move into caves.", "Cave salamanders born without eyes had increased fitness and produced more offspring than the salamanders with eyes.", "A mutagenic pollutant in the environment eliminated the trait for eyes in the cave salamander."], "answer": 3, "keywords": ["evolution", "cave salamanders", "natural selection", "fitness", "offspring", "mutations", "mutagenic"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-12-q8", "unit": 1, "question": "Which of the following is NOT true of the connections between cells?", "options": ["Plasmodesmata are channels that pass between the cell walls of adjacent plant cells, connecting their cytoplasm.", "Tight junctions are a watertight seal between two adjacent animal cells.", "Desmosomes are short microtubules that connect adjacent cells in plants.", "Gap junctions are channels that allow for transport and communication between animal cells.", "The collagen fibers of the extracellular matrix hold cells together to form a tissue."], "answer": 2, "keywords": ["cell connections", "plasmodesmata", "tight junctions", "desmosomes", "gap junctions", "extracellular matrix", "collagen", "cytoplasm"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-12-q9", "unit": 8, "question": "Evidence shows that grazing can improve grass health due to increased rate of nutrient cycling in the soil and the stimulation of shoot growth through pruning of the main plant shoots. This plant - herbivore interaction is best described as", "options": ["mutualism.", "commensalism.", "parasitism.", "competition.", "biomagnification."], "answer": 0, "keywords": ["grazing", "nutrient cycling", "shoot growth", "herbivore", "mutualism", "commensalism", "parasitism", "competition", "biomagnification"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-12-q10", "unit": 3, "question": "During glycolysis, NAD+ accepts 1 proton and 2 electrons to become NADH. In this process, the NAD+ molecule has been", "options": ["hydrolyzed.", "hydrogenated.", "denatured.", "oxidized.", "reduced."], "answer": 4, "keywords": ["glycolysis", "nad+", "nadh", "proton", "electrons", "reduction", "oxidation", "hydrolyzed", "denatured"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-12-q11", "unit": 4, "question": "Scientists studying fruit flies discovered displaced and duplicate body parts on some flies. For example, some flies had feet rather than mouth parts, an extra pairs of wings, or legs growing from their heads. These anomalies are due to mutations in the", "options": ["homeotic genes.", "p53 gene.", "egg polarity genes.", "Cdk genes.", "tumor suppressor gene."], "answer": 0, "keywords": ["fruit flies", "mutation", "homeotic genes", "p53", "egg polarity", "cdk", "tumor suppressor", "hox genes"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-12-q12", "unit": 8, "question": "Which of the following must be subtracted from gross primary productivity to calculate net primary productivity?", "options": ["The total energy stored in the autotrophs.", "The energy used by the autotrophs in respiration.", "The total energy stored in the heterotrophs.", "The energy used by the heterotrophs in respiration.", "The energy converted to carbohydrates during photosynthesis."], "answer": 1, "keywords": ["gross primary productivity", "net primary productivity", "autotrophs", "respiration", "heterotrophs", "photosynthesis", "carbohydrates"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-12-q13", "unit": 5, "question": "In sheep, white wool is dominant to black wool. In a certain flock of sheep, 90% of the sheep have white wool. Assuming that the population is in Hardy Weinberg equilibrium, what percentage of the population is homozygous for white wool?", "options": ["32", "43", "46", "68", "90"], "answer": 2, "keywords": ["hardy-weinberg", "equilibrium", "dominant", "homozygous", "white wool", "black wool", "allele frequency"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-12-q16", "unit": 7, "question": "Which of the following is NOT a characteristic of vertebrates?", "options": ["High degree of cephalization", "Endoskeleton made of bone or cartilage", "Open circulatory system", "Hollow dorsal nerve cord", "Excretory system with a pair of kidneys"], "answer": 2, "keywords": ["vertebrates", "cephalization", "endoskeleton", "bone", "cartilage", "circulatory system", "nerve cord", "kidneys"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-12-q17", "unit": 1, "question": "Contractile vacuoles would most likely be found in unicellular organisms that are", "options": ["internal parasites.", "external parasites.", "isotonic to their environment.", "in a freshwater environment.", "in a marine environment."], "answer": 3, "keywords": ["contractile vacuoles", "unicellular", "freswater", "marine", "parasites", "isotonic", "osmoregulation"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-12-q18", "unit": 5, "question": "A woman with type AB blood marries a man with type B blood. Their first child has type A blood. What is the probability that the second child will also have type A blood?", "options": ["100%", "75%", "50%", "25%", "0%"], "answer": 3, "keywords": ["blood type", "type ab", "type b", "type a", "probability", "punnett square", "genetics"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-12-q19", "unit": 9, "question": "At any given time, 5-10% of the body's capillaries contain blood. If all capillary beds were to open at once,", "options": ["blood pressure would fall dramatically.", "blood would move too rapidly through the body.", "blood volume would increase.", "gas exchange in the lungs would increase to allow for strenuous exercise.", "the kidneys would produce more urine."], "answer": 0, "keywords": ["capillaries", "blood pressure", "blood volume", "gas exchange", "lungs", "kidneys", "urine"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-12-q20", "unit": 7, "question": "Which of the following is NOT a plant adaptation specifically for a terrestrial environment?", "options": ["Roots", "Xylem", "Cell walls", "Waxy cuticle", "Seeds"], "answer": 2, "keywords": ["plant adaptation", "terrestrial", "roots", "xylem", "cell walls", "waxy cuticle", "seeds"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-13-q1", "unit": 10, "question": "Lyme disease is a bacterial infection that is transmitted by the", "options": ["flea.", "tsetse fly.", "mosquito.", "tick.", "chigger."], "answer": 3, "keywords": ["lyme disease", "bacterial infection", "flea", "tsetse fly", "mosquito", "tick", "chigger"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-13-q2", "unit": 3, "question": "Glycolysis is a sequence of chemical reactions that convert glucose into two pyruvic acids, resulting in a net gain of two ATP molecules. During glycolysis, this ATP is generated by", "options": ["chemiosmosis.", "photophosphorylation.", "substrate level phosphorylation.", "the electron transport chain.", "hydrolysis."], "answer": 2, "keywords": ["glycolysis", "glucose", "pyruvic acids", "atp", "chemiosmosis", "photophosphorylation", "substrate level phosphorylation", "electron transport chain", "hydrolysis"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-13-q3", "unit": 4, "question": "Gene amplification involves the", "options": ["unwinding of the chromosome in areas undergoing transcription.", "presence of multiple copies of a gene.", "transformation of a gene from a recessive to a dominant trait.", "lengthening of the polyA tail to increase translation time.", "transformation of the gene into a cancerous gene."], "answer": 1, "keywords": ["gene amplification", "chromosome", "transcription", "polya tail", "translation", "recessive", "dominant", "cancerous gene"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-13-q4", "unit": 10, "question": "A patient presented with painful muscle spasms, stiffness in the jaw, difficulty swallowing, and rigid abdominal muscles. The most likely diagnosis would be", "options": ["tetanus.", "diphtheria.", "anthrax.", "cholera.", "meningitis."], "answer": 0, "keywords": ["muscle spasms", "stiffness", "jaw", "tetanus", "diphtheria", "anthrax", "cholera", "meningitis"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-13-q5", "unit": 1, "question": "Which of the following is a difference between viruses and viroids?", "options": ["Viruses contain introns, but viroids have only exons.", "Viruses infect eukaryotic cells, and viroids infect prokaryotes.", "Viruses have genomes composed of DNA, but viroids have genomes composed of RNA.", "Viruses can enter the host cells, but viroids can only attach the cell surface.", "Viruses have capsids, but viroids do not."], "answer": 4, "keywords": ["viruses", "viroids", "introns", "exons", "eukaryotic", "prokaryotes", "dna", "rna", "capsids"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-13-q7", "unit": 9, "question": "The heartbeat is initiated by the", "options": ["SA node.", "AV node.", "cerebrum.", "spinal cord.", "hypothalamus."], "answer": 0, "keywords": ["heartbeat", "sa node", "av node", "cerebrum", "spinal cord", "hypothalamus"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-13-q8", "unit": 2, "question": "If the M checkpoint of the cell cycle is not cleared, the cell will not proceed to", "options": ["S phase.", "G2 phase.", "prophase.", "metaphase.", "anaphase."], "answer": 4, "keywords": ["m checkpoint", "cell cycle", "s phase", "g2 phase", "prophase", "metaphase", "anaphase"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-13-q9", "unit": 9, "question": "In the nephron, blood pressure forces fluid from the capillaries of the glomerulus across the epithelium of the Bowman's capsule into the lumen of the nephron tubule. This filtrate does not contain", "options": ["glucose.", "urea.", "water.", "plasma proteins.", "electrolytes."], "answer": 3, "keywords": ["nephron", "glomerulus", "bowman's capsule", "filtrate", "glucose", "urea", "plasma proteins", "electrolytes"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-13-q11", "unit": 3, "question": "During oxidative phosphorylation of cellular respiration, the final electron acceptor of the electron transport chain is", "options": ["ADP.", "NAD.", "water.", "citrate.", "oxygen."], "answer": 4, "keywords": ["oxidative phosphorylation", "cellular respiration", "electron transport chain", "electron acceptor", "adp", "nad", "water", "citrate", "oxygen"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-13-q12", "unit": 7, "question": "Transformation involves", "options": ["bacteria incorporating new foreign DNA from their surroundings.", "the creation of a strand of mRNA from a DNA template.", "the transfer of DNA to a bacterial cell by a virus.", "the production of a protein from a mRNA transcript.", "the transfer of DNA from one bacterium to another through a pilus."], "answer": 0, "keywords": ["transformation", "bacteria", "dna", "mrna", "virus", "protein", "pilus"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-13-q13", "unit": 8, "question": "The dispersion pattern of humans in the United States can best be described as", "options": ["clumped.", "random.", "innate.", "uniform.", "homogenic."], "answer": 0, "keywords": ["dispersion pattern", "humans", "clumped", "random", "uniform"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-13-q15", "unit": 7, "question": "Fruits have contributed to the success of angiosperms by", "options": ["aiding in the dispersal of seeds by wind and animals.", "attracting insects to the pollen inside.", "producing diploid cells through double fertilization.", "providing nutrients for the plant.", "producing eggs and sperm inside a protective covering."], "answer": 0, "keywords": ["fruits", "angiosperms", "seeds", "dispersal", "pollen", "double fertilization"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-13-q17", "unit": 4, "question": "In a repressible operon, transcription of the structural gene", "options": ["starts when the pathway's substrate is present.", "stops when the pathway's substrate is present.", "starts when the pathway's product is present.", "stops when the pathway's product is present.", "occurs continuously."], "answer": 3, "keywords": ["repressible operon", "transcription", "structural gene", "substrate", "product"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-13-q19", "unit": 1, "question": "Which of the following is not a step involved in the production and distribution of glycoprotein for export?", "options": ["A carbohydrate is attached to the newly formed protein in the ER.", "The protein is moved from the ER to the Golgi by transport vesicle.", "The Golgi body fuses with the cell membrane to release the glycoprotein by exocytosis.", "The protein is synthesized on the ribosome.", "The glycoprotein is tagged for export in the Golgi body."], "answer": 2, "keywords": ["glycoprotein", "er", "golgi body", "vesicle", "exocytosis", "ribosome", "export"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-13-q20", "unit": 6, "question": "Antimicrobial resistance (AMR) is one of the top global public health threats. These varieties of bacteria probably developed as a result of", "options": ["natural selection.", "hybrid vigor.", "coevolution.", "adaptive radiation.", "bottleneck effect."], "answer": 0, "keywords": ["antimicrobial resistance", "bacteria", "natural selection", "hybrid vigor", "coevolution", "adaptive radiation", "bottleneck effect"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-Inv-q1", "unit": 6, "question": "Which of the following is NOT a condition of Hardy-Weinberg equilibrium in populations?", "options": ["No genes may enter or leave the gene pool.", "Matings must be random.", "Natural selection must occur.", "Mutations cannot occur.", "All are conditions."], "answer": 2, "keywords": ["hardy-weinberg", "equilibrium", "population", "genes", "gene pool", "matings", "natural selection", "mutations"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-Inv-q2", "unit": 2, "question": "In which phase of the cell cycle is DNA replicated?", "options": ["Mitosis", "G1 phase", "G2 phase", "S phase", "G0 phase"], "answer": 3, "keywords": ["cell cycle", "dna", "replicated", "mitosis", "g1 phase", "g2 phase", "s phase", "g0 phase"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-Inv-q4", "unit": 9, "question": "How is the structure of the small intestine adapted to its function?", "options": ["The small intestine has a flap that prevents the regurgitation of food back into the respiratory system.", "Villi on the small intestine's inner lining increase its surface area for increased nutrient absorption.", "The small intestine is relatively short to allow for faster digestion.", "The muscular lining of the small intestine grinds up food into smaller pieces.", "A mucus lining minimizes damage from the small intestine's extremely acidic contents."], "answer": 1, "keywords": ["small intestine", "villi", "surface area", "nutrient absorption", "digestion", "mucus"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-Inv-q5", "unit": 2, "question": "The enzyme that joins nucleotides in specific order to create a new DNA strand is called", "options": ["DNA polymerase.", "DNA helicase.", "reverse transcriptase.", "DNA spliceosome.", "DNA ligase."], "answer": 0, "keywords": ["enzyme", "nucleotides", "dna strand", "dna polymerase", "dna helicase", "reverse transcriptase", "dna spliceosome", "dna ligase"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-Inv-q6", "unit": 8, "question": "Which of the following is a characteristic typical of K-selected populations?", "options": ["Organisms reproduce early in life.", "Many offspring are produced at one time.", "Offspring are typically small.", "Parents produce a few offspring per reproductive cycle.", "Parents do not care for the young after birth."], "answer": 3, "keywords": ["k-selected", "populations", "offspring", "reproduce", "reproductive cycle"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-Inv-q7", "unit": 8, "question": "Which of the following organisms would be most likely to exhibit uniform dispersion?", "options": ["Jaguars, who actively defend their territories", "Sunflowers, which grow on the disturbed ground on the edges of plowed fields", "Carpenter ants, which burrow into trees for food and shelter.", "Oysters, which attach to hard surfaces such as piers and pilings", "Fire ants, which live in colonies underground"], "answer": 0, "keywords": ["uniform dispersion", "jaguars", "sunflowers", "carpenter ants", "oysters", "fire ants", "territories"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-Inv-q8", "unit": 1, "question": "A bag made of a selectively permeable membrane contains a 0.2M starch solution. It is placed in a beaker with a 0.4M starch solution. How will the molecules move across the membrane to try to reach equilibrium?", "options": ["Water and starch will move into the bag.", "Water and starch will move out of the bag.", "Water will move into the bag, but starch will not move across the membrane.", "Water will move out of the bag, but starch will not move across the membrane.", "Starch will move into the bag, but water will show no net movement across the membrane."], "answer": 3, "keywords": ["osmosis", "selectively permeable membrane", "starch", "solution", "equilibrium", "concentration gradient"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-Inv-q9", "unit": 3, "question": "The evolutionary advantage of aerobic respiration over anaerobic respiration is that aerobic respiration", "options": ["can occur without the presence of oxygen.", "has a greater ATP yield per carbohydrate.", "can occur in the cytosol of the cell.", "allows for faster cell reproduction.", "requires fewer enzymes."], "answer": 1, "keywords": ["aerobic respiration", "anaerobic respiration", "atp", "carbohydrate", "oxygen", "metabolism"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-Inv-q10", "unit": 6, "question": "In isolation, groups of individuals in a population become separated from each other by barriers such as rivers, mountains, or bodies of water, preventing the exchange of genetic materials.", "options": ["temporal", "behavioral", "geographic", "postzygotic", "mechanical"], "answer": 2, "keywords": ["isolation", "population", "barriers", "geographic", "genetic materials", "speciation"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-Inv-q11", "unit": 1, "question": "What mitochondrial characteristic indicates that they are descendants of free-living prokaryotes?", "options": ["Mitochondrial ribosomes are similar to bacterial ribosomes.", "Each mitochondrion contains its own DNA.", "Mitochondria can synthesize their own proteins.", "Mitochondria can reproduce independently of the cell.", "All of these are correct."], "answer": 4, "keywords": ["mitochondria", "prokaryotes", "ribosomes", "dna", "proteins", "endosymbiotic theory"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-Inv-q13", "unit": 9, "question": "The function of neurotransmitters in the neuron are to", "options": ["transmit the nervous impulse down the dendrite.", "activate the sodium-potassium pump.", "produce epinephrine to increase nervous response.", "transmit the nervous impulse across the synapse.", "transmit messages from the brain to the peripheral nerves."], "answer": 3, "keywords": ["neurotransmitters", "neuron", "synapse", "dendrite", "sodium-potassium pump", "epinephrine", "impulse"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-Inv-q14", "unit": 1, "question": "Which of the following does NOT describe the plasma membrane?", "options": ["Lipid bilayer", "Hydrophobic exterior; hydrophilic interior", "Embedded protein carriers", "Contains cholesterol for fluidity", "Semipermeable"], "answer": 1, "keywords": ["plasma membrane", "lipid bilayer", "hydrophobic", "hydrophilic", "protein carriers", "cholesterol", "semipermeable"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-Inv-q15", "unit": 10, "question": "What is the function of reverse transcriptase in retroviruses?", "options": ["It destroys the host cell's DNA.", "It transcribes viral RNA into DNA inside the host cell.", "It transcribes host cell RNA into viral DNA.", "It catalyzes the production of viral proteins at the host ribosome.", "It causes the host cell to lyse, releasing phages."], "answer": 1, "keywords": ["reverse transcriptase", "retroviruses", "rna", "dna", "host cell", "viral proteins", "ribosome"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-Inv-q16", "unit": 5, "question": "A woman with type B blood has a child with type O blood. The father CANNOT have blood type", "options": ["A", "B", "AB", "O", "More than one of these answers is correct."], "answer": 2, "keywords": ["blood type", "inheritance", "mendelian", "alleles", "genotype"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-Inv-q17", "unit": 10, "question": "Viruses can be considered obligate parasites, because viruses", "options": ["can insert their DNA into the host DNA.", "live inside the host cell, using its energy for survival.", "use raw materials from the host cell to make more viruses.", "are nonliving.", "are unicellular heterotrophs."], "answer": 2, "keywords": ["viruses", "obligate parasites", "host cell", "dna", "nonliving", "heterotrophs"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-Inv-q18", "unit": 3, "question": "Photorespiration is the accumulation of oxygen in the photosynthetic tissues of plants; it causes the rate of photosynthesis to decrease in these plants.", "options": ["oxygen; decrease", "oxygen; increase", "carbon dioxide; increase", "carbon dioxide; decrease", "water; increase"], "answer": 0, "keywords": ["photorespiration", "oxygen", "photosynthesis", "carbon dioxide", "plants"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-Inv-q19", "unit": 4, "question": "During the process of replication, the DNA code that was ATGCCATG was copied as AGGCCATG. What type of mutation occurred?", "options": ["Insertion", "Deletion", "Translocation", "Substitution", "Duplication"], "answer": 3, "keywords": ["mutation", "replication", "dna", "substitution", "insertion", "deletion", "translocation", "duplication"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-DWU-q1", "unit": 10, "question": "A viral infection that causes fatigue, headaches, stiffness, limb pain, and paralysis of breathing muscles is", "options": ["ALS (amyotrophic lateral sclerosis)", "poliomyelitis", "tetanus", "diphtheria", "multiple sclerosis"], "answer": 1, "keywords": ["viral infection", "fatigue", "paralysis", "breathing muscles", "poliomyelitis"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-DWU-q2", "unit": 2, "question": "If nondisjunction occurs in meiosis II during gametogenesis, what cells will be produced at the completion of meiosis?", "options": ["Two of the gametes will be haploid, and two will be diploid.", "There will be an extra gamete.", "One gamete will be n+1, one gamete will be n-1 and two gametes will be n.", "Two gametes will be n+1 and two gametes will be n-1.", "All the gametes will be diploid."], "answer": 2, "keywords": ["nondisjunction", "meiosis ii", "gametogenesis", "gametes", "haploid", "diploid", "n+1", "n-1"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-DWU-q4", "unit": 1, "question": "Cell signaling involves converting extracellular signals to specific responses inside the target cell. In the initial response to a signal, the cell experiences", "options": ["a change in receptor conformation.", "the influx of ions.", "an increase in protein kinase activity.", "G protein activation.", "an increase in DNA transcription."], "answer": 0, "keywords": ["cell signaling", "extracellular signals", "target cell", "receptor conformation", "protein kinase", "g protein", "transcription"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-DWU-q5", "unit": 7, "question": "Some strains of the streptococcus bacterium secrete poisonous substances called exotoxins. The genes that code for exotoxins are believed to have originated in viruses. Which of the following is the most likely mechanism by which the bacteria acquired the ability to produce the exotoxins?", "options": ["Viral DNA became integrated into the bacterial chromosome during the viral reproductive cycle.", "Viral exotoxin proteins were transported into the bacterial cell by endocytosis.", "Bacterial cells engulfed fragments of DNA from dead bacteria.", "Environmental conditions activated dormant genes in the bacterial genome.", "The virus incorporated bacterial genes into its own genome, allowing it to develop the cellular structures of the bacteria."], "answer": 0, "keywords": ["streptococcus", "exotoxins", "viruses", "bacterial chromosome", "viral dna", "horizontal gene transfer", "transduction"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-DWU-q6", "unit": 1, "question": "A mutation occurred in a cell which prevented the synthesis of histones. What effect would this have on the cell?", "options": ["Tumor suppressor genes would be activated, and the cell would undergo rapid cell division.", "Translation of genes would be inhibited.", "The cell's DNA could not be packed into its nucleus.", "The electron transport chain would halt due to its inability to recycle electrons.", "Spindle fibers would not form during prophase."], "answer": 2, "keywords": ["mutation", "histones", "dna", "nucleus", "chromatin packing"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-DWU-q8", "unit": 1, "question": "The IV solutions administered to patients are normally isotonic to the blood. Which of the following is most likely to occur if an IV of distilled water is administered?", "options": ["The volume of blood will increase, causing an increase in heart rate.", "The respiratory rate will increase to expel excess water through vapor.", "The cells that are exposed to the IV solution will expand as water moves into the cells by osmosis.", "The cells that are exposed to the IV solution will shrink as they lose water by osmosis.", "Phagocytic cells will consume excess water and transport it to the kidneys."], "answer": 2, "keywords": ["iv solutions", "isotonic", "distilled water", "osmosis", "hypotonic"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-DWU-q9", "unit": 2, "question": "Cytokinesis usually follows mitosis. If the cell completed mitosis but not cytokinesis, the result would be", "options": ["a single cell with one nucleus containing twice as much DNA as the parent cell.", "a single cell with one nucleus containing half as much DNA as the parent cell.", "two cells with nuclei that contain twice as much DNA as the parent cell.", "one cell with two nuclei each containing the same amount of DNA as the parent cell.", "one cell with two nuclei each containing twice as much DNA as the parent cell."], "answer": 3, "keywords": ["cytokinesis", "mitosis", "nucleus", "dna", "multinucleated"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-DWU-q10", "unit": 8, "question": "A marine species was removed from a tide pool community, causing a significant reduction in species richness. The species was probably a", "options": ["keystone species.", "low yield producer.", "strong competitor.", "species in great abundance.", "detrivore."], "answer": 0, "keywords": ["marine species", "tide pool", "community", "species richness", "keystone species"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-DWU-q11", "unit": 9, "question": "Infants who are born prematurely do not have a substance called _______ in their lungs. This substance helps lower the surface tension for better gas exchange and keeps the smallest branches of the respiratory system called the _______ from collapsing.", "options": ["pleura, alveoli", "pleura, bronchioles", "surfactant, alveoli", "surfactant, bronchioles", "mucus, bronchioles"], "answer": 2, "keywords": ["infants", "lungs", "surface tension", "gas exchange", "respiratory system", "surfactant", "alveoli"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-DWU-q12", "unit": 9, "question": "The action potential of a nerve involves a sequence of permeability changes that depolarizes and then repolarizes the membrane of a neuron. The depolarization of the neuron is due to the", "options": ["potassium gates closing.", "release of cAMP in the cytosol.", "sodium gates opening.", "inactivation of the Na+K+ pump.", "hyperpolarization of the neural membrane."], "answer": 2, "keywords": ["action potential", "nerve", "depolarization", "neuron", "sodium gates", "permeability"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-DWU-q13", "unit": 3, "question": "In the eukaryotic cell, glycolysis takes place in/on the _______, the Krebs' Cycle in/on the _______ and oxidative phosphorylation in/on the _______", "options": ["Cytosol, mitochondrial matrix, inner membrane of the mitochondria", "mitochondrial matrix, cytosol, cytosol", "Cytosol, cytosol, inner membrane of the mitochondria", "Cytosol, inner membrane of the mitochondria, mitochondrial matrix", "mitochondrial matrix, mitochondrial matrix, inner membrane of the mitochondria"], "answer": 0, "keywords": ["eukaryotic cell", "glycolysis", "krebs cycle", "oxidative phosphorylation", "cytosol", "mitochondrial matrix", "inner membrane"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-DWU-q14", "unit": 4, "question": "The first codon in a gene on the template strand of DNA is often ATG, which codes for methionine. What will be the base sequence on the tRNA anticodon that carries methionine to the site of translation?", "options": ["ATG", "GTA", "TAC", "UAC", "AUG"], "answer": 4, "keywords": ["codon", "gene", "template strand", "dna", "methionine", "trna", "anticodon", "translation"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-DWU-q16", "unit": 5, "question": "A man with Duchenne muscular dystrophy has a child with a woman who does not carry or have the genetic trait. What are the chances that their son will have DMD?", "options": ["100%", "75%", "50%", "25%", "0%"], "answer": 4, "keywords": ["duchenne muscular dystrophy", "genetic disorder", "recessive", "sex-linked", "inheritance", "punnett square"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-DWU-q17", "unit": 2, "question": "Which of the following statements is true of a species that has the chromosome number 2n=16?", "options": ["A gamete from the species has four chromosomes.", "The diploid cell from the species has 8 pairs of homologous chromosomes.", "The diploid cell from the species has 16 homologous chromosome pairs.", "The species is diploid with 32 chromosomes.", "After the S phase, its cells will contain 16 chromosomes."], "answer": 1, "keywords": ["chromosome number", "diploid", "gamete", "homologous chromosomes", "s phase"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-DWU-q19", "unit": 5, "question": "You genetically engineer a bacterial cell that is unable to synthesize restriction enzymes. What effect would this have on the bacterium?", "options": ["The cell would be easily infected and lysed by bacteriophages.", "The cell would be unable to replicate its DNA.", "The cell could not form a pilus to transfer a copy of its plasmid to another bacterium.", "The cell would become parasitic to obtain nutrients.", "The cell would be unable to synthesize proteins on its ribosomes."], "answer": 0, "keywords": ["genetically engineer", "bacterial cell", "restriction enzymes", "bacteriophages", "dna technology"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-State-q1", "unit": 10, "question": "Tuberculosis is a disease caused by the bacterium called mycobacterium tuberculosis. Tuberculosis spreads to the air from one person to another when they cough, speak or sing. A current outbreak of tuberculosis is proving to be resistant to standard treatments. As of January 2025, 66 people in this state have contracted the disease.", "options": ["Florida", "California", "Arizona", "Texas", "Kansas"], "answer": 4, "keywords": ["tuberculosis", "mycobacterium tuberculosis", "bacterium", "resistant", "standard treatments", "outbreak", "kansas"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-State-q2", "unit": 1, "question": "The functional group aids in the formation of tertiary structure of proteins by forming strong bonds called bridges between parts of the protein chain.", "options": ["hydroxyl", "amine", "sulfhydryl", "carboxyl", "aldehyde"], "answer": 2, "keywords": ["functional group", "tertiary structure", "proteins", "sulfhydryl", "disulfide bridges", "protein chain"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-State-q3", "unit": 3, "question": "In cellular respiration, the energy for most of the ATP synthesis is supplied by", "options": ["high energy phosphate bonds in organic molecules.", "a proton gradient across a membrane.", "converting oxygen to ATP.", "transferring electrons from organic molecules to pyruvate.", "generating carbon dioxide and oxygen in the electron transport chain."], "answer": 1, "keywords": ["cellular respiration", "atp synthesis", "energy", "proton gradient", "membrane", "chemiosmosis", "oxidative phosphorylation"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-State-q4", "unit": 8, "question": "Clear cutting is a tactic used in the logging industry by which all trees in an area are cut at once. This method is most efficient for both harvesting and replanting trees. It is also used to clear land for agricultural use. However, clear cutting in the tropical rainforest produces agricultural land with limited productivity, because", "options": ["the rate of decomposition is high in the tropics but primary production is low.", "the soil in the rainforest is toxic to most food crops due to high levels of heavy metals.", "the majority of the rainforest ecosystem's nutrients are stored in the forest trees not in the soil.", "rainforest trees regrow rapidly and inhibit crop growth.", "the tropical rainforest is too hot for most food crops."], "answer": 2, "keywords": ["clear cutting", "logging industry", "tropical rainforest", "agricultural land", "productivity", "nutrients", "ecosystem"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-State-q5", "unit": 5, "question": "In a population of 250 individuals, 40 individuals show the recessive trait. If the population is at Hardy Weinberg equilibrium, how many individuals will be homozygous dominant for the trait?", "options": ["90", "100", "120", "150", "210"], "answer": 0, "keywords": ["population", "recessive trait", "hardy weinberg", "equilibrium", "homozygous dominant", "allele frequency"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-State-q6", "unit": 1, "question": "Changing a single amino acid in a protein consisting of 325 amino acids would", "options": ["always alter the primary structure of the protein, but never its tertiary structure or function.", "always cause the tertiary structure of the protein to unfold.", "always alter the biological activity or function of the protein.", "always alter the primary structure of the protein and disrupt its biological activity.", "always alter the primary structure of the protein, sometimes alter the tertiary structure of the protein and affect its biological activity."], "answer": 4, "keywords": ["amino acid", "protein", "primary structure", "tertiary structure", "biological activity", "mutation"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-State-q8", "unit": 9, "question": "Which of the following hormones is incorrectly paired with its origin?", "options": ["Progesterone - ovary", "Growth hormone - pituitary gland", "Insulin-pancreas", "Melatonin - pineal gland", "Antidiuretic hormone - adrenal gland"], "answer": 4, "keywords": ["hormones", "progesterone", "ovary", "growth hormone", "pituitary gland", "insulin", "pancreas", "melatonin", "pineal gland", "antidiuretic hormone", "adrenal gland"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-State-q9", "unit": 5, "question": "Determine the phenotypic ratio of possible offspring in a cross between a homozygous tall, homozygous yellow pod pea plant and a pea plant that is homozygous tall and heterozygous for pod color. (T= tall, G= green pod, t= short, g= yellow pod)", "options": ["3 tall, green: 1 short, green", "1 tall, green: 1 tall, yellow", "3 tall, green: 1 tall, yellow: 3 short, green: 1 short, yellow", "1 tall, green: 1 tall, yellow: 1 short, green: 1 short, yellow", "9 Tall, green, 3 tall, yellow: 3 short, green: 1 short, yellow"], "answer": 1, "keywords": ["phenotypic ratio", "offspring", "homozygous", "heterozygous", "pea plant", "pod color", "punnett square"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-State-q10", "unit": 2, "question": "How do homologous chromosomes differ from each other?", "options": ["Number of base pairs that they contain.", "The type and relative position of the genes present on the chromosome.", "The position of the centromere on each chromosome.", "The precise sequence of the DNA on each chromosome.", "They do not differ from each other; they are identical copies."], "answer": 3, "keywords": ["homologous chromosomes", "genes", "centromere", "dna sequence", "alleles"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-State-q12", "unit": 9, "question": "During fetal development in males, testicles move from the lower abdomen into the scrotum. If the testicles do not drop by six months after birth, pediatricians recommend surgery to correct the condition, because undescended testicles can lead to", "options": ["infertility due to a higher than normal temperature in the testes which affects sperm maturation.", "infertility due to the inability of the prostate gland to release its secretions into the semen.", "urination difficulties due to the narrowing of the urethra.", "difficulty in locomotion due to the lack of a counterbalance provided by the scrotum.", "the absence of secondary sex characteristics due to decreased production of testosterone."], "answer": 0, "keywords": ["fetal development", "testicles", "scrotum", "infertility", "sperm maturation", "testes"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-State-q13", "unit": 6, "question": "When considering evolution, the more closely related two different organisms are, the", "options": ["less likely it is that they were acted on by natural selection.", "fewer mutations occurred in their genomes.", "more fit they are.", "more recently they shared a common ancestor.", "more likely it is that genetic drift occurred."], "answer": 3, "keywords": ["evolution", "organisms", "natural selection", "mutations", "common ancestor", "phylogeny"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-State-q16", "unit": 7, "question": "Which of the following is NOT a characteristic of the phylum Cnidaria?", "options": ["Bilateral symmetry", "Gastrovascular cavity", "Nematocysts", "Two body plans: medusa and polyp", "Nerve net for sensory and motor functioning"], "answer": 0, "keywords": ["phylum cnidaria", "bilateral symmetry", "gastrovascular cavity", "nematocysts", "medusa", "polyp", "nerve net"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-State-q17", "unit": 4, "question": "For a repressible operon to be transcribed,", "options": ["RNA polymerase and the active repressor must be present.", "RNA polymerase must bind to the promoter and the repressor must be inactivated.", "RNA polymerase cannot be present and the repressor must be inactive.", "the corepressor must bind to the operator so that RNA polymerase can bind to the promoter.", "the substrate must bind to the repressor to transform it into an inducer."], "answer": 1, "keywords": ["repressible operon", "transcribed", "rna polymerase", "repressor", "promoter", "gene expression"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-State-q18", "unit": 4, "question": "The hormone epinephrine stimulates a signaling pathway that results in the breakdown of glycogen to glucose in the liver cells. Which of the following describes how epinephrine initiates glycogen breakdown in a cell?", "options": ["Epinephrine is taken into the cell by endocytosis; glycogen moves into the vesicle containing epinephrine, and is converted to glucose.", "Epinephrine diffuses through the plasma membrane and binds with glycogen; glucose is produced from this reaction.", "Epinephrine diffuses through the plasma membrane and travels to the endoplasmic reticulum; this activates the embedded ribosomes to produce the enzymes to break down glycogen.", "Epinephrine binds to a cell surface receptor; the receptor is now activated and catalyzes the reaction to convert glycogen to glucose.", "Epinephrine binds to a cell surface receptor; the activated receptor stimulates the production of a second messenger CAMP, which causes an increase in the rate of glycogen degradation."], "answer": 4, "keywords": ["epinephrine", "signaling pathway", "glycogen", "glucose", "liver cells", "cell surface receptor", "camp", "second messenger"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-State-q19", "unit": 9, "question": "Which of the following is NOT a method used by thermoregulators to increase the rate of metabolic heat production?", "options": ["non shivering thermogenesis", "storage of brown fat in tissues", "shivering and vasoconstriction", "evaporation of sweat", "counter current heat exchange in extremities"], "answer": 3, "keywords": ["thermoregulators", "metabolic heat production", "non shivering thermogenesis", "brown fat", "shivering", "vasoconstriction", "evaporation", "sweat", "counter current heat exchange"] },
    { "id": "24-25-TMSCA-State-q20", "unit": 2, "question": "During replication, the new DNA strand is formed in the 5' to 3' direction because", "options": ["the charge on the 3' end of a DNA molecule prevents the addition of nucleotides.", "methylation of the 5' telomere prevents the addition of nucleotides.", "DNA molecules uncoil the 5' end of the template first.", "DNA polymerase can only add nucleotides to the 3' end of the growing strand.", "DNA polymerase can only add nucleotides to the 5' end of the growing strand."], "answer": 3, "keywords": ["replication", "dna strand", "5' to 3' direction", "nucleotides", "dna polymerase", "template"] }
]